<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[www.staxcycleclub.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[A sleek studio in Inglewood, YYC turned virtual]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/feed</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 10:20:02 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[How Yoga Can Improve Your Posture &#38; Why You Should Care]]></title><description><![CDATA[Having good posture isn’t just about looks, either. There are many health benefits that come with standing or sitting correctly for our body]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/how-stax-yoga-can-improve-your-posture-and-why-you-should-care</link><guid isPermaLink="false">62844d3b920cf607fa6f0df5</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><category><![CDATA[strength training]]></category><category><![CDATA[fitness hacks]]></category><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 02:09:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/85bcec_89d553bc47a44f9abfb5e05e1cd35e4e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Remember when you were young, and your mom would yell at you to stand up straight? You probably responded with an eye roll or heavy sigh, but now that we’re older, we realize mom was right. </p>

<p>Having good posture isn’t just about looks, either. There are many health benefits that come with standing or sitting correctly for our body. Keeping a neutral spine is easier for some people than for others. But as with most things in life, if we dedicate a little bit of focus and practice to the problem, we can improve it! And one of the best ways to improve our posture is through yoga. With our new Stax Yoga classes, we’ll have you standing up straight in no time!</p>
<h4>Health Benefits of Good Posture</h4><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_edc75fee3b3547d2bd0c65104015d3dc~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Bad posture is especially common for those who work all day at a computer. Better posture can eliminate neck pain as well as offer many other health benefits." alt="A woman rubs her neck at her office desk."></figure><p>If you’ve ever spent all day hunched over a computer, there’s no doubt you’ve felt some neck or back pain caused by poor posture. But correcting this issue and sitting or standing properly has benefits well beyond helping a sore spine. <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/fitness-exercise/posture-benefits#11.-Appear-taller-" target="_blank" ><u>Good posture</u></a> also improves how some organ systems function as well. </p>
<h4>Eliminate Pain in Your Back and Neck</h4>
<p>Improper posture sees your pelvis, torso, and head stacked in a way that causes stress, and therefore pain, in your back and neck. Strengthening the proper muscles that support your spine and standing or sitting with good posture should relieve that achy back. This will, in turn, lower the tension you feel in your shoulders or neck.</p>
<h4>Minimize Headaches</h4>
<p>That tension we create with poor posture often affects more than our shoulders and neck. It can also contribute to tension headaches. This is especially true for those who sit or stand with a forward head - typical for anyone working at a computer all day. Others store this tension in their jaw, which can cause TMJ.</p>

<p>We can either eliminate, minimize, or shorten these headaches by correcting our posture.</p>
<h4>Improve Organ Function</h4>
<p>Most of us are aware of how posture can affect our muscles, joints, and bones, but few realize how much it can affect other organ systems in our body. By correcting our posture, we can improve lung capacity, circulation, and digestion. </p>

<p>Slouching compresses your lungs, so when you stand up straight and tall, you give them more room to expand properly. Unfortunately, this compression also affects other vital organs, affecting proper circulation and digestion. Good posture will allow the free flow of blood, food, and digestive juices.</p>
<h4>Make You Appear Taller </h4>
<p>Straight up and simple; good posture will make you appear taller. And who doesn't want that?!</p>
<h4>Boost Your Energy and Your Mood</h4>
<p>Last but certainly not least comes the positive effects for your mind! Having good posture can improve your energy levels throughout the day. This is because when you are using your muscles as they are meant to be used, they don’t fatigue as quickly. Good posture preserves your energy for other things. Good posture can also improve your mood, concentration, and even self-confidence.</p>
<h4>Good Posture is Also Important While Exercising</h4><p>Other types of exercise can also help improve posture, including <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/our-favorite-resistance-bands-how-to-use-them" target="_blank" ><u>core or back exercises</u></a>. But even more important is your posture <em>when</em> exercising.</p>

<p>Proper form while exercising is crucial to prevent injuries or strains caused by performing exercises improperly. Improving your posture through yoga will also help guarantee that you’re using the proper form during other physical activities. This not only prevents injury but also improves results.</p>
<h4>Does Yoga Improve Posture?</h4><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_a7649d46254d4f6088a53b282b56f45e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Downward Dog is one yoga pose that helps improve posture. " alt="A woman does downward dog between two plants. "></figure><p>Practicing yoga isn't the end-all cure, but it definitely helps us begin our journey towards good posture. Yoga does three main things for us when we're on this journey:</p><ol>
  <li>Strengthens our back and core muscles</li>
  <li>Improves our spine's mobility</li>
  <li>Makes us more self-aware of our body positioning (perhaps the most important) </li>
</ol><p>Plenty of yoga poses open the chest and shoulders, lengthen the spine, or create more flexibility. The main focus on poses, however, is <strong>body alignment</strong>. By focusing on this throughout the practice, we become much more in tune with ourselves. This connection will help you notice when you slump into bad posture in your day-to-day life.</p>
<h4>8 Yoga Poses to Help Correct Posture</h4>
<p>Pretty much any style of yoga and any pose that you do during your practice will help your posture. But some poses focus a bit more on areas that will correct your posture, like opening the shoulders or lengthening the spine. </p>

<p>Here are some beginner poses you can try at home, but remember that executing the pose properly is crucial. So come practice with us at the gym or check out<a href="https://www.yogajournal.com/poses/library/" target="_blank" > <u>The Pose Library</u></a> at the Yoga Journal to make sure you're doing the poses correctly.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_b2fe7d260f7049c589a49bcb995d8f9d~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png" title=" Mountain pose focuses on stacking your ribs on top of your pelvis and your pelvis on top of your feet. " alt="A group of women in yoga class does mountain pose."></figure><h4>Mountain Pose </h4><p>While this pose might not seem like it’s doing much, it is actually the perfect pose to work on posture. Make sure to focus on each part of the body and where it is stacked up. This pose is a foundational pose for any yoga practice.</p>
<h4>Cow Face</h4><p>By stretching your entire body, you have a chance to feel the differences on either side of the body. You must be careful to keep the spine straight, bringing awareness to your posture.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_75d729ef2b5243c4a09d0a56b523e2db~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Flow through cat and cow to lengthen your spine." alt="Woman in the yoga pose cow"></figure><h4>Cat-Cow</h4><p>This is a flow between two poses that extends and flexes the spine, increasing mobility and flexibility. Practicing this pose often will show you the natural curve of your spine, which helps you arrive at neutral more easily.</p>
<h4>Seated Twist</h4><p>A few seated twist poses are great for posture, but beginners can start with this basic seated twist. It will help elongate and stretch the spine.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_b36b5bc8d35641e49e783d746882d26a~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Cobra pose lengthens the space between the vertebrae in the spine while opening the chest. " alt="A woman practices cobra pose."></figure><h4>Cobra Pose</h4><p>Cobra pose is a beginner backbend that will open the chest and stretch the shoulders. It also lengthens the spine and can relieve back pain.</p>
<h4>Wide-Legged Bend</h4><p>This pose stretches the hamstrings, lengthening the lower back. It can also provide relief from neck and shoulder tension.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_818eeeda03d7459f8723ac427ddad695~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Extend and stretch your entire back with standing forward fold." alt="3 people in the yoga pose standing forward fold"></figure><h4>Standing Forward Fold</h4><p>This simple pose is often misunderstood and taken for granted. Its purpose is to extend and stretch the entire back body, from the lower back through the neck. </p>
<h4>Downward Dog</h4><p>While difficult for beginners, this position eventually becomes a resting pose. It opens the shoulders and chest while straightening and aligning the spine.</p>
<h4>Want to get your flow on?</h4><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/85bcec_cd5b7e4ff04a420f9af1cc3a04937f3b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Image: 6ix Flow" ></figure><p>If you're ready to get bendy and improve that posture, we highly recommend checking out a class with our friends at 6IX Flow...</p>

<p>Located in the lower level of 720 17 Ave SW, 6IX Flow is a music driven, candle-lit, sweat-infused hot yoga practice to help you connect movement to breath with full intention, while connecting to your body and the beat.</p>

<p>Use promocode <a href="http://www.6ixflow-calgary.com/" target="_self" >STAXFLOWS</a> for a class on the house! (Select ‘financially secure’ from the sliding scale drop-in to redeem code.)</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/85bcec_f39258bbebd4445a984907167ce45f48~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Image: 6ix Flow" ></figure> ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Your Pelvic Floor - All You Need to Know and More]]></title><description><![CDATA[Let’s normalize talking about our pelvic floors, ladies! Sometimes things become normalized in our heads that really shouldn’t. A little...]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/your-pelvic-floor</link><guid isPermaLink="false">621021de653528cbc245eaf2</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[pregnancy fitness]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy habits]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 20:18:47 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_344363fa795942e7b8db3a7f0afdc798~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let’s normalize talking about our pelvic floors, ladies! Sometimes things become normalized in our heads that really shouldn’t. A little leaking urine when you sneeze, painful sex, or feeling the need to constantly pee may slowly become normal to us over time, but the truth is that all the symptoms may be a sign of an overactive pelvic floor. </p>

<p>That being said, if we talk about these issues, we can normalize talking about women’s health and sexuality - a big win for everyone! So let’s get into the nitty-gritty of our pelvic floors, how to know if ours is healthy or overactive, and what we can do to promote pelvic floor health!</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_aa7cd70c78554959b94276fee164d1e3~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Time to normalize talking about our pelvic floor health!" alt="Woman holding a vaginal weight in front of her pelvis"></figure><h2><strong>Do Only Women Have a Pelvic Floor?</strong></h2>
<p>Both men and women have a pelvic floor! The groups of muscles have some similarities and some differences. In both men and women, these muscles:</p><ul>
  <li>Support your internal organs</li>
  <li>Allow you to control bodily movements</li>
  <li>Help circulate lymphatic fluid from the legs back to the heart</li>
  <li>Are essential for sexual function</li>
</ul><p>For women, the pelvic floor has the extra task of supporting the uterus. </p>

<p>It’s important to keep your pelvic floor muscles strong and not too tight. Both weak or hypertonic (too tight) pelvic floor muscles can cause issues with your health. But what many of us don’t realize is that some of our day-to-day habits might be contributing to damaging them.</p>

<p>There’s a TikTok making the rounds from <a href="https://www.jpost.com/health-and-wellness/dont-diss-your-piss-this-habit-can-harm-your-bladder-678614" target="_blank" ><u>Dr. Alicia Jeffrey-Thomas</u></a> who is letting us in on a little secret - peeing in the shower could be setting us up for pelvic floor dysfunction down the road.</p>
<h2><strong>Is My Pelvic Floor Healthy?</strong></h2>
<p>Basically, the sign of a healthy pelvic floor is the lack of symptoms relating to urination, defecation, and sex. Things should be operating smoothly down there, without pain or much difficulty.</p>

<p><strong>Some signs that your pelvic floor is functioning properly are:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>No leakage when you cough, sneeze, laugh, or jump</li>
  <li>Passing bowel movements easily</li>
  <li>Not having heaviness or bulging in the vagina</li>
  <li>Having pain free sex</li>
  <li>Being able to hold a pee or fart in</li>
  <li>Having a mild urge to open your bladder that you can delay if required</li>
</ul><h2><strong>Pelvic Floor Dysfunction Is More Common Than You Think</strong></h2>
<p>Many of the symptoms of an overactive pelvic floor might appear slowly, and with time you might get used to them and not realize the bigger problem. Women are often afraid to talk with their doctors or even their friends about these issues since they can be considered rather personal. Problems like these are actually quite common and nothing to be embarrassed about.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_02eabae8a949469f83f5ff54032d4daf~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Pelvic floor dysfunction is more common than you think" alt="A woman experiencing abdominal pain and clutching her stomach"></figure><p>In fact, almost<a href="https://columbiasurgery.org/colorectal/pelvic-floor-disorders-frequently-asked-questions" target="_blank" > ,<u>a quarter of women suffer from pelvic floor disorders</u></a>. You should never be afraid to bring up any concerns with your doctor. </p>

<p><strong>Some of the following symptoms may be caused by pelvic floor dysfunction:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>Bladder frequency</li>
  <li>Pain with a tampon or menstrual cup use</li>
  <li>Lower back and pelvic pain</li>
  <li>Abdominal pain or discomfort with bowel movements</li>
  <li>Pain during sex</li>
</ul><p>Most pelvic floor dysfunction is a result of the muscles being either too weak or too tight. A <em>hypertonic</em> pelvic floor occurs when your muscles become too tense and struggle to relax. A weak pelvic floor is considered <em>hypotonic</em>. </p>
<h2><strong>Causes of Pelvic Floor Issues</strong></h2>
<p>Unfortunately, some causes of pelvic floor issues cannot be prevented. Some are natural and some may result from outside forces outside of our control. Other causes are silly mistakes we make in our everyday life that we can take control of today.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_c82aa157b1fa40afb6f3462375f5c885~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Pregnancy can cause pelvic dysfunction" alt="Pregnant woman holding her belly"></figure><p><strong>Causes of pelvic floor dysfunction include:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>Pregnancy and childbirth</li>
  <li>Old age</li>
  <li>Being overweight</li>
  <li>Traumatic injuries or surgery </li>
  <li>Straining on the toilet</li>
  <li>Heavy lifting or high impact exercise</li>
</ul><h2><strong>Bad Habits to Stop Today</strong></h2>
<p>While some causes of pelvic floor dysfunction are outside of our control, women also often have some habits we don’t even realize can contribute to these problems. Most of these revolve around straining or relaxing our muscles when we shouldn’t.</p>

<p><strong>Peeing in the shower: </strong>There are two sides to this in general - those who love to pee in the shower and those who think it’s gross. If you’re on the former team, unfortunately, it’s time to put a stop to this. <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@scrambledjam?referer_url=https://www.cosmopolitan.com/uk/body/health/a37316316/pee-in-shower-tiktok/&#38;referer_video_id=6956594764888198406&#38;refer=embed" target="_blank" >,<u>@scrambledjam</u></a> let us know that not only does peeing in the shower teach us to subconsciously need to pee when we hear running water, but also our pelvic muscles can properly relax when we’re standing. That means we likely don’t release all the urine, causing issues later. So try to resist the urge and pee before or after your shower.</p> <p><strong>Hovering on the toilet seat: </strong>We know, sometimes you’re out and about, and the toilet seat is too gross to sit on. But, hovering over the toilet seat instead of sitting down activates the muscles that we really need to relax. So, instead of hovering, clean the seat or use a protective cover.</p>

<p><strong>Straining on the toilet: </strong>No one really wants to talk about this, but straining on the toilet is all around no good for your health. It can cause pelvic muscle dysfunction along with many other health issues, so it’s best to avoid it altogether. Keep your digestive tract as healthy as possible by staying hydrated and eating nutritious foods. If you do have issues, seek medical help to avoid permanent damage.</p>

<p><strong>Sitting too much: </strong>While this is the common position for many jobs today, the human body was designed to spend all day sitting in a chair. Just like the rest of our muscles, our pelvic floor can get lazy when it does nothing all day. If you do have to sit, make sure you keep good posture and avoid pelvic tilt. Try to get up and walk or stretch when you have a moment to take a break.</p>
<h2><strong>Pelvic Floor Muscle Exercises</strong></h2>
<p>The good news about discussing these problems with your doctor is that you can do things to improve control of your pelvic floor muscles. Like any other muscle in your body, you can exercise them to do their job better.</p>

<p>Not all pelvic floor dysfunction is caused by the same problem, and therefore not all will have the same solution. Kegel exercises can often help for a weak pelvic floor, while a hypertonic pelvic floor might respond better to stretching and relaxing.</p>

<p>Healthline<a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/fitness-exercise/pelvic-floor-exercises#exercises" target="_blank" > ,<u>highlights some great exercises</u></a> for both issues on their website. However, it’s always best to consult a doctor.</p>

<p>If you’re experiencing any of these symptoms, don’t accept them as a normal part of life or aging. Instead, open up the conversation to make discussing women’s health issues more normalized and consult a doctor on steps or medications that may help you get back to a healthy pelvic floor, leading you to a much happier life. Bonus points if you follow <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@scrambledjam?referer_url=https://www.cosmopolitan.com/uk/body/health/a37316316/pee-in-shower-tiktok/&#38;referer_video_id=6956594764888198406&#38;refer=embed" target="_blank" >,<u>@scrambledjam</u></a> on TikTok as she “breaks it down on the pelvic dance floor!”</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Strength Training is Important]]></title><description><![CDATA[Why Strength Training is Important Can you believe the pandemic started over two years ago now?! More importantly, it's been nearly two...]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/why-strength-training-is-important</link><guid isPermaLink="false">625db4e315b91442d37454f0</guid><category><![CDATA[strength training]]></category><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[cardiovascular training]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 17:51:03 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_2e25cb05037f46ccab8dee9fee06c8ea~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Why Strength Training is Important</p>

<p>Can you believe the pandemic started over two years ago now?! More importantly, it's been nearly two years of Stax classes being entirely virtual, and well, to be honest, we miss your faces! So it's no surprise that we are beyond stoked to be back in the <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/studio" target="_blank" ><u>studio </u></a><u> </u>(a brand new studio at that)! We are rocking a new location with killer amenities and tons of parking to make your Stax Cycle Club studio experience even better than before.</p>

<p>Of course, we still have your favorite spin classes with our marvelous trainers that you've come to know and love, but we're also expanding our services. Now you can swing by for a spin class, yoga class, or one of our new Stax Strong strength training classes. These 45-minute classes set to the beat will work your lungs, heart, and muscles! So if you love our spin classes but are new to the world of strength training, keep reading to discover all the positive benefits that come along with it!</p>

<p>What is Strength Training Anyway?</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_644d3a0508e54f899e07df65c0899c6e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  alt="Stax instructor holding a medicine ball in one hand"></figure><p>Strength training is any physical exercise designed to improve strength and endurance. Also known as resistance training, you don't need massive barbells to rock out these exercises. Instead, you can use dumbbells, kettlebells, bodyweight, medicine balls, or <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/our-favorite-resistance-bands-how-to-use-them" target="_blank" ><u>resistance bands</u></a>. </p>

<p>Our Stax Strong classes blend weight segments with core work and cardio, giving you a well-balanced and diverse workout that will build your strength and confidence like never before. Of course, it wouldn't be a proper Stax class without some uplifting beats to keep you pumped through the end of the workout.</p>


<p>5 Reasons You Should Join a Stax Strong Class</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_eca87f8e84964799976d1d50fd19e100~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Strength training can do more than just build muscle." alt="Woman lying on the floor performing a chest press exercise with a dumbbell"></figure><p>Strength training obviously can make you stronger, but it has many other <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/fitness/benefits-of-strength-training" target="_blank" ><u>benefits</u></a> that you probably don't realize. These classes can help:</p><ul>
  <li>Lower your risk of multiple diseases</li>
  <li>Strengthen more than just your muscles</li>
  <li>Improve your day-to-day life</li>
</ul><h6><strong>Improves Strength</strong></h6>
<p>Okay, this one should be pretty obvious as it's the primary goal of strength training, but hear us out! Even if you don't have a burning desire to get stronger, gaining muscle mass makes even simple daily tasks much easier, like:</p><ul>
  <li>Picking up your kids</li>
  <li>Opening that jar of pickles</li>
  <li>Making taking the stairs instead of the elevator more effortless</li>
</ul><h6><strong>Prevents Injuries of All Types</strong></h6>
<p>On top of increasing muscle mass, strength training improves mobility and flexibility. It also can increase bone density.</p>

<p>These bonus benefits can help prevent injury by strengthening tendons and ligaments and lowering the risk of bone fractures. In addition, as we age, we begin to lose muscle mass. By continuing strength training, we can help minimize muscle loss over the years.</p>
<h5><strong>Keeps Your Heart Healthy</strong></h5>
<p>We're already doing wonders for our heart, respiratory, and circulatory systems with our spin class cardio. But, by adding strength training to the mix, we can do even more good for our bodies!</p>

<p>Strength training has been shown to lower blood pressure, strengthen the heart and blood vessels, manage blood sugar levels, and help control cholesterol. All of these benefits can help keep your heart healthy and lower the risk of heart disease.</p>
<h5><strong>Burns Calories Like Crazy</strong></h5>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_e80abd7f0ee249f89e1d05debac23b38~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Lifting weights can help increase your metabolism." alt="Woman braced on a workout bench performing a back exercise with a dumbbell"></figure><p>Stronger muscles mean that you'll be burning calories more <em>effectively</em>. Your metabolism will be pumping, which helps you get leaner and melt off fat.</p>

<p>Sure, those might be superficial benefits, but it's also highly beneficial to your health. Excess body fat is linked to heart disease, diabetes, and even some types of cancer. By staying healthy, you can lower your chances of being affected by these diseases.</p>
<h6><strong>Benefits the Mind, Body, and Soul</strong></h6>
<p>There are countless ways that strength training can help your mind and soul flourish. For starters, it can do wonders for your self-confidence. As you begin to witness yourself overcome difficult challenges and lift heavier weights, you'll be rewarded with improved self-esteem.</p>

<p>This type of exercise also releases endorphins which can help elevate moods and even lower anxiety and depression. Studies show that strength training can also improve memory and cognitive function in the brain. Every part of you will benefit from strength training!</p>

<p>The Dream Team - Strength Training and Cardio</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_819da23139fe4d3bb024d7f409e6721b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Stax has the dream team: strength training and cardio!" alt="Women participating in a group fitness class"></figure><p>Peanut butter and jelly. Tom and Jerry. Macaroni and cheese. Cheech and Chong. Some things are just better in pairs - like strength training and cardio! If you're super into one of them, it's time to add the other to your weekly schedule. And that's easier than ever at our new studio! Combining the two types of exercises, either on the same day or alternating, will make you a more well-rounded athlete and help you reap the most health benefits possible. </p>

<p>For our cycle junkies who love cardio but are hesitant to add strength training, the benefits will spill over into your spin class. Your endurance will improve along with your form, positively impacting your cycling. While you're at it, you'll burn even more calories than before, thanks to increased metabolism.</p>

<p>For those who already love hitting the weights, adding cardio is equally beneficial. And I have good news for you! Some cardio actually builds muscle at the same time as increasing your endurance. Spin class, for example, helps build lean muscle, and high-intensity interval training crushes calories while increasing strength in the whole body.</p>

<p>New Studio, New Stax</p>

<p>At Stax, we officially have it all! Our classic spin classes are a fun cardio workout that will have you sweating from head to toe. The new Stax Strong classes combine cardio with weight segments, giving you the best of both worlds. Not to mention, you can also check out one of our Spin x Strong sessions if you want to ride and weight train on the same day!</p>

<p>On recovery days, you can still swing by the Stax studio and join one of our replenishing yoga classes. With expanded class options and new brilliant amenities, the new Stax Studio will quickly become your favorite one-stop shop for all things fitness. We can't wait to have our Stax fam back in the studio and to see all of your smiling faces in real life!</p>

<p><strong>Curious to try out a strength class? </strong></p>

<p><strong>Use promo code "STRONG" for 50% off a strength class drop-in! (*limit 1/member, offer expires May 15)</strong></p>

<p><strong>PLUS earn an extra bonus 50 points every time you attend a Stax Strong class from now until May 15!</strong></p>
 
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_c8bd871504a849fd88a09afddd394e00~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Stax All Access Memberships are here! " alt="Decorative - Meme of Kim Kardashian and her children."></figure>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Get Up Off Your Glutes, Girls + Guys!]]></title><description><![CDATA[If you’re wondering what the heck is a posterior chain, we’re not surprised. And we’re here to fill you in!]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/get-up-off-your-glutes-girl</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6232889e5aee09c0fc48650e</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><category><![CDATA[strength training]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 15:55:18 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_9660a6f677824b278a7e75f0d36aa3a1~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We can all get a little bit complacent sometimes. It’s just human nature. But one place you shouldn’t allow yourself to slack off is during your <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/studio" target="_blank" ><u>spin class</u></a> at STAX. Your instructor isn’t shouting at you to stand up just to torture you. There’s a good reason why we want you to get up out of your saddle. Posterior chain activation, baby!</p>

<p>If you’re wondering what the heck is a posterior chain, we’re not surprised. And we’re here to fill you in! If we tell you the method behind the madness, will you get your butt out of that saddle a bit faster next time? </p>
<h2><strong>Use It or Lose It - Booty Edition</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_d72fcb95d2344b3ea855e82a3a84157e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_736,h_491,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Sitting at desks for work all day can make our glutes lazy." alt="A peach on a pink background."></figure><p>Despite how things are today, our bodies just weren’t designed to be sitting at a desk all day. We were supposed to be constantly on the move. But many of us now lead a relatively inactive life thanks to our jobs, among other things. As the largest muscles in our body, our glutes are meant to be in action all day. So when we let them fully relax sitting behind a desk all day, they get lazy.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.amg-osteo.com/" target="_blank" >,<u>Alice Monger-Godfrey</u></a>, an Osteopath at AMG Osteo Clinics, <a href="https://www.cyclingweekly.com/fitness/training/recruit-glutes-make-biggest-muscle-body-389060" target="_blank" ><u>clearly explains the problem for</u></a> non-medical folk:</p><blockquote>“Working at a desk compresses your spine when you’re slumped. The back muscles are forced to overwork, and the glutes become lazy, so you get a complete mismatch. We’re going from two extremes - sedentary to asking a lot of them.”</blockquote><h2><strong>Posterior Chain, Activate!</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_423a629894d941f1ab43c8debe91f202~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_795,h_530,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Your posterior chain is made up of the muscles on the back side of your body." alt="A woman flexing her back muscles."></figure><p>Okay, so now we understand why our lifestyle can impact our glute strength, what can we do about it? We can combat this issue by lifting up out of our saddles to activate our posterior chain. The posterior chain is basically all the muscles that make up your backside - namely the glutes, hamstrings, calves, and back.</p>

<p>Your posterior chain is responsible for tons of your daily movements - from things as simple as lifting your arms, picking something up off the ground, or jumping. Perhaps even more important than that, a strong posterior chain:</p><ul>
  <li>Helps prevent injuries and premature wear and tear on joints</li>
  <li>Boosts your athletic performance</li>
  <li>Helps keep your body in the correct posture</li>
  <li>Even boosts your metabolism</li>
</ul><p>The posterior chain does a lot for you, so you should take care of it too. So, get up off your glutes!</p>
<h2><strong>We Know It’s Hard - Reasons You Should Get Your Butt Up</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_cd6c0ee2bdac4bd18c02161cb059a8f8~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Getting up during your cycle class benefits your body in multiple ways." alt="Emily activates her posterior chain by lifting up out of her saddle."></figure><p><strong>The main reason we encourage everyone to get out of the saddle is to help strengthen the posterior chain.</strong> By standing up, we shift the activity into our quads, glutes, and calves. We can help correct the imbalance that so many of us have between our anterior and posterior chains by targeting these muscles.</p>

<p>Not only does getting out of the saddle strengthen our posterior chains, but <strong>it also increases our performance on our bikes. </strong>When we stand up, we automatically shift our weight slightly forward. This helps us get more leverage for those intense climbs during class. You can also maintain a much higher rhythm when you're out of the saddle. A higher rhythm means a higher power output.</p>

<p>On top of increasing your rhythm and power output, <strong>this position helps engage muscles that you might not be utilized otherwise</strong>. In this position, you'll be forced to engage your upper body and your core, as well as your glutes. Plus, you can give your tooshy a break from being sat on.</p>
<h4><strong>Tips For Hardcore Activation</strong></h4><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_28d73155903946459c9fa87c3335d2ef~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_795,h_530,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Mastering the correct position is important when it comes to getting up out of your seat." alt="A woman activates her posterior chain by standing up while cycling. "></figure><p>We've covered the <em>why</em>, but you may still be confused about <em>how</em>. The first part is easy - when your instructor says stand up, you stand up! But we have a few tips to help you get into the proper position for the ultimate posterior chain activation.</p>

<p><strong>Crank that resistance: </strong>To simulate climbing a hill, turn that sprint shift all the way to the right. With the resistance up and pedaling in the standing position, you can hit that higher rhythm and maximize your power output.</p>

<p><strong>Don’t lean too far forward: </strong>While we want to shift our weight slightly forward from the seated position, you want to avoid overdoing it. The ideal position will have your weight directly over the pedals.</p>

<p><strong>Keep your glutes back over the seat</strong>: An excellent way to make sure that you're not leaning too far forward is to make sure your glutes are above the seat. Again, be mindful of your posture and keep your knees bent and your weight evenly distributed.</p>
<h2><strong>Other Ways to Strengthen Your Posterior Chain</strong></h2>
<p>If you’re having issues relating to having a weak posterior chain, there are other exercises you can go on top of riding standing up to help strengthen it. Workouts that extend and contract the muscles along your backside can help with this. By doing these exercises alongside your spin classes (hello, <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/studio" target="_blank" ><u>Staxables</u></a>), you’ll see a significant improvement in posterior chain strength.</p>

<p>These <a href="https://www.masterclass.com/articles/posterior-chain-exercises-list#what-are-posterior-chain-exercises" target="_blank" ><u>five exercises for your posterior chain</u></a> can strengthen your muscles, reduce pain in the back, and help your posture.</p><ul>
  <li>Kettlebell swings</li>
  <li>Single-leg glute bridges</li>
  <li>Back squats</li>
  <li>Sumo squats</li>
  <li>Glute-ham raises</li>
</ul><p>So, next time your instructor calls for a heavy climb, get up and out of the saddle and work those posterior chain muscles! </p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Don’t and Dos of New Spin Shoes]]></title><description><![CDATA[So you’ve just had your first spin class, and you’re immediately hooked! Trust us - we get it. Or, maybe you’ve been taking spin classes...]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/the-don-t-and-dos-of-new-spin-shoes</link><guid isPermaLink="false">62057f4d6486f53f4a9ba95e</guid><category><![CDATA[fitness equipment]]></category><category><![CDATA[cardiovascular training]]></category><category><![CDATA[spin shoes]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 23:07:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/85bcec_1be3ede3235442a38d25df8054a98d5d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_480,h_480,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So you’ve just had your first spin class, and you’re immediately hooked! Trust us - we get it. Or, maybe you’ve been taking spin classes with us for a while, and you think it’s time to up your shoe game and officially “lock-in.” Whatever the reason is that you’re in the market for new spin shoes, it can be a very overwhelming world!</p>

<p>As always, Stax has got you covered! We’re breaking down the complexities of spin shoes so you can figure out which option is best for you. It’s not about finding the best indoor cycling shoes on the market. It’s about finding the best spin cycle shoes for you!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_7fcb878c45154c269e00e46323cbb0f4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  alt="A woman shopping for indoor cycling shoes"></figure><p>Ready to get <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/stax-your-way-back-on-track" target="_blank" ><u>back on track with Stax</u></a>? We have a ton of amazing in-person (!) and virtual classes. </p> 
<h2>What To Look For in a Spin Shoe</h2>
<p>When it comes to shopping for the best indoor cycling shoes, there are three components you need to pay attention to - <strong>the shoe, cleat,</strong> and <strong>pedal</strong>.</p>

<p>Typically, you’ll want to buy a shoe that works with the pedal system on <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/5-best-spin-bikes-for-home" target="_blank" ><u>your spin bike</u></a>, whether that’s at home or in the Stax studio.</p>
<h6><strong>Types of Pedals</strong></h6><p>There are three types of pedals that you may encounter on a spin bike:</p><ul>
  <li>Flat</li>
  <li>Toe cages</li>
  <li>Clip-ins</li>
</ul><p>Which pedals you're using may depend on what your bike came with or your own personal preference. </p>
<h6><strong>Flat Pedals</strong></h6><p>Think of flat pedals as the OG pedal - like you used to have on your bike as a kid. Flat pedals are what we're used to on the original design of a bike, and they still work great for basic biking needs.</p>

<p>Some spin bikes may come with flat pedals, but it's no longer the norm after the introduction of more advanced pedals. If your bike has flat pedals, you can always swap them out for cages or clip-ins. </p>

<p><strong>Pros: </strong>Can be used with any shoe and you’re free to adjust your foot however you want.</p>
<p><strong>Cons: </strong>Less efficient than other pedals.</p>
<h6><strong>Toe Cages</strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_546156225e194d0d97bc31dfc2fd0514~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Toe cages will work with regular sneakers work for spin classes." alt="Pink sneakers in toe cages on a spin bike."></figure><p>Cages can take your power and efficiency to the next level because you can now both <em>push</em> and <em>pull </em>while pedaling. Like flat pedals, they can be used with any shoe and are relatively easy to get in and out of, but you get a bit more security, and you're unlikely to slip out while riding.</p>

<p><strong>Pros: </strong>More efficient and powerful strokes. No specific shoe is necessary.</p>
<p><strong>Cons: </strong>Need to be tightened each time you use them. Don't have a firm grip around your shoe.</p>
<h6><strong>Clip-Ins</strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_089d486d2ca34158b813560be2683ea5~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_850,h_620,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Clip-in or "clip-less" pedal option" alt="Close up shot of a clip-in pedal for spin cycle"></figure><p>Also called "clip-less" (confusing, we know), <a href="https://www.bicycling.com/bikes-gear/a20025552/5-great-reasons-to-start-using-clipless-pedals/" target="_blank" ><u>clip-ins</u></a> lock your feet into the pedals for the highest power and efficiency possible.</p>

<p>There is a bit of a learning curve with clip-ins, as you'll need to learn how to lock in and release your shoes. But once you get the hang of it, you'll feel totally connected with your bike and ready to kick your spin class's butt.</p>

<p>All classes at Stax (online and in-studio) are coached with clip-in shoes!</p>

<p><strong>Pros: </strong>Ultimate power and efficiency, and your feet won’t slip from the pedal.</p>
<p><strong>Cons: </strong>Can take a little bit to get used to, and you’ll need specific shoes to match your pedals.</p>
<h2><strong>Types of Indoor Cycling Shoes</strong></h2>
<p>Just as there are different styles of pedals, there are different types of spin bike shoes. Which style of spin cycle shoes you choose for yourself will depend on the pedals installed on the bike you want to ride.</p>

<p>Don't worry, though. If you decide it's time to make a change, you can easily swap out the pedals on your bike to work with the shoes you prefer.</p>

<p>Your indoor cycling shoes <strong>must </strong>have cleats if you want to use clip-in pedals. Typically there are two styles of cleats: SPD or LOOK Delta. (Hold onto that thought, and we'll learn more about cleats shortly!)</p>
<h6><strong>MTB Shoes</strong></h6><p>Mountain bike shoes (MTBs) are built for use with mountain bikes but also work for spin class. These types of shoes are compatible with SPD cleats. They’re designed to give you the maximum control of your pedals with their grippy bottom and allow for toe-in or toe-out positioning.</p>
<h6><strong>Road Shoes</strong></h6><p>Road shoes are designed for road cyclists and therefore are very lightweight and sturdy. These types of shoes are compatible with LOOK Delta cleats. They are great for when your body is in the same position for a long time but don't allow as much movement.</p>
<h6><strong>Universal Shoes</strong></h6><p>Considering that as spin cyclists, we're not headed for the streets or the mountains, we love the fact that now there is a hybrid shoe that gives us the best of both worlds. These <a href="https://www.amazon.com/CyclingDeal-Universal-9-Degree-Floating-Compatible/dp/B08KDD82VV" target="_blank" ><u>universal shoes</u></a> can clip into both SPD and LOOK Delta cleats. </p>
<h6><strong>Sneakers</strong></h6><p>If you're not planning on using clip-in pedals, you don't need to purchase special shoes. You can wear regular sneakers with flat pedals and toe cages. This is a great idea for beginners who are still getting used to being on a bike.</p>
<h2><strong>What About Cleats</strong></h2>
<p>You might not guess that there's a huge difference between having two clips or three clips when considering your cleat system. However, LOOK Delta and SPD cleats each have their different specific uses.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_ae15657394494c59bc098af8577e57e4~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_850,h_620,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="SPD cleats and LOOK Delta cleats" alt="SPD cleats and LOOK Delta cleats"></figure><h6><strong>LOOK Delta</strong></h6><p>LOOK Delta cleats are typically used with street bikes and also the now super popular Peloton.</p>

<p>Delta cleats have a three-hole cleat system that makes a triangle shape. They are generally more rigid and therefore allow for more power transfer.</p>

<p>At Stax, we use SPD Keo Look cleats. You can find them <a href="https://www.bikeinn.com/bike/look-keo-grip-cleats/11580/p?utm_source=google_products&#38;utm_medium=merchant&#38;id_producte=91829&#38;country=ca&#38;gclid=Cj0KCQiAmeKQBhDvARIsAHJ7mF5M4cGbScyGjw-tlH8-eV9owDPh5NZcR8VkFp5IibW28npiJNu0lqAaArtZEALw_wcB&#38;gclsrc=aw.ds" target="_blank" ><u>here</u></a>. </p>
<h6><strong>SPD</strong></h6><p>Designed by Shimano, SPD cleats are used mostly with mountain bikes.</p>

<p>They use two bolts and are the most common cleat systems used in spin studios. Shoes with these cleats also tend to be easier to walk in, although still not ideal.</p>
<h6><strong>Shoes that work for both</strong></h6><p>Say you have a Peloton at home, but your spin studio uses SPD clips. You might want to look into universal shoes, which can clip into both types of systems. These might also be the best indoor cycling shoes for you if you enjoy road biking, mountain biking, spinning, or any combination of the three.</p>
<h2><strong>Our Favs</strong></h2>
<p>Wow, that was a lot of information about shoes! Who knew the world of indoor cycling shoes could be so complicated? If you’re still a little confused about what direction you want to head, here's some of our favorite shoes you can find at Stax (psst. shoe rentals are free with classes)!</p>

<p><strong>Ladies</strong></p>
<p>While we have a few brands in the mix, our primary ladies shoe is Diadora.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_f10f20d6391d4edbb1e52d2ce3312922~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_988,h_708,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Check out these neon green Diadora spin bike shoes on Amazon!" alt="Bright green Diadora spin shoes"></figure><p>We love Diadora shoes because:</p><ul>
  <li>They have a stiff and sturdy sole that helps us hit it hard for those heavy climbs.</li>
  <li>They also have a breathable liner which is perfect for the hot and sweaty spin room. </li>
</ul><p>While they may be a bit pricy, these shoes seem to last forever and and we believe are absolutely worth the investment and still look and work great.</p>

<p>When it comes to cleats, positioning is everything. This varies from person to person, so you have to find out what works for you. As a guideline, we recommend placing the cleat at the ball of your foot to give maximum power. </p>

<p><strong>Unisex & Mens</strong></p>
<p>Our favorite unisex shoe is the dhb Troika Road Shoe. It provides a firm, wider base with easy Velcro straps to secure your fit. </p>


<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_efed6a0a15d04a6f8336f6e9ad997943~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_497,h_379,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>These shoes can be hard to track down, but <a href="https://www.chainreactioncycles.com/ca/en/dhb-troika-road-shoe/rp-prod164188" target="_blank" ><u>Chain Reaction Cycles</u></a> has a decent selection and often replenishes it's stock. </p>
<h6><strong>Janelle's Shoe</strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_d9073519454d4f2181ec7d35074e67b5~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_646,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Another Giro favorite are these Giro Espada E70s on Amazon." alt="White women’s Giro spin shoes"></figure><p>Janelle hit the jackpot with the very first pair that she ever bought for herself. Despite having tried out other shoes since then, the Giro EC70 remains her favorite to this day. She loves how secure they feel on her feet and how they're super breathable. She would buy them again in a heartbeat!</p>
<h6><strong>Lindsay's Shoe</strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_45399749a34544979f48fdc5d965579c~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Lindsay loves her Nike SuperRep Cycling shoes" alt="Pink Nike SuperRep Cycle shoes"></figure><p>Lindsay was on the nice list this year and Santa brought her a new pair of Nike SuperRep Cycle shoes! </p>

<p>Not only is the color fabulous - who doesn't love metallic pink? - but these shoes are made for intense movement.</p>

<p>They have a breathable liner and lightweight mesh on the top to keep your foot cool during the sweatiest classes. These spin shoes are also compatible with two standard types of cleats so you can mix and match to whatever suits your needs. </p><hr><p>If you already have a pair of spin shoes - which are your ride or die? Share below in the comments!</p>



]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Self-Care Tips to Beat the Winter Blues]]></title><description><![CDATA[Don't let the winter blues get you down. Here are 10 self-care tips to add to your daily life to stay healthy and happy.]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/self-care-tips-to-beat-the-winter-blues</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61eef3b601efd0001653c434</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[mindset]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy habits]]></category><category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2022 18:13:02 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_7d440a41ba024048b3c3f5f10993d61a~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_0c256e2efb03441389c4371f4655bf0c~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_768,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><a href="https://standasa.com/product/spin-and-strength-class-with-joelle-tomlinson/" target="_blank" ><u>Click here</u></a> to sign-up for Joelle's charity ride</p>

<p>This winter has been cold, team! Like, really, really cold. But we’re not going to let these negative temperatures give us a negative state of mind. With the holiday season over and the chilly winter weather in full swing, it’s more important for us to amp up the self-care to defeat season blues. </p>
<h2>10 Self-Care Tips</h2>
<p>While extra streamy bubble baths with fizzy bath bombs are a crucial part of our self-care routines, we can do some other things to care for ourselves on a deeper level. So here are some simple ways to take care of yourself after the holidays!</p>
<h6><strong>Create a Morning Routine</strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_f5ca6813e07544efbade326a1e3cff24~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="A morning routine can look how ever you want it to" alt="A good book and a fresh cup of coffee first thing in the morning."></figure><p>There are two types of people out there: those who love a routine and those terrified by them. But science is hard to argue with, and routines are proven to positively affect our mental health. According to <a href="https://www.realsimple.com/work-life/life-strategies/benefits-of-routines" target="_blank" >,<u>Real Simple</u></a>, routines help us:</p><ul>
  <li>Maintain healthy habits</li>
  <li>Fight against depression</li>
  <li>Lower anxiety levels</li>
  <li>Help us focus on more important things that need our time</li>
</ul><p>By creating a healthy morning routine for yourself, you’ll be less likely to procrastinate beginning your day, start off on the right foot, and stick to the healthy habits you want to keep. </p>

<p>Our favorite morning ritual routines that you could incorporate are:</p><ol>
  <li>Stretching and/or a gentle yoga practice</li>
  <li>Journaling</li>
  <li>Running</li>
  <li>A healthy breakfast</li>
  <li>Mediation</li>
</ol><p>The key is to create a morning routine that works and feels good for <em>you</em>.</p>
<h6><strong>Respect Your Budget</strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_2a31e805cd084d6c8f4e2b14913ab6e3~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Plan early this year and set up a budget to keep your spending on track." alt="A laptop and planner prepared to assist in making a yearly budget."></figure><p>Most of us probably don’t think of budgeting as a form of self-care, but we should! Anything that positively affects our mental health can be considered self-care; making responsible financial decisions fits the bill.</p>

<p>By making a budget for yourself and sticking to it, you’re practicing self-control and organizing your life. Money has always been one of the most significant contributors to stress and anxiety for adults. If you stick to your budget now, you’ll be able to save up money for emergencies and lower your stress down the line. Plus, you’ll be able to treat yourself every now and then, which can also be great for your mental health.</p>
<h6><strong>Take Time For Yourself</strong></h6>
<p>Throughout the holiday’s it seems like we have one social obligation after the next. Between friends and family, we forget to stop and take time for ourselves. So, if you felt overwhelmed over the past few months, now is the perfect time to slow down and have that alone time that you need.</p>

<p>Don’t be afraid to say no to invitations. If your house is full, and it seems like you can’t get away, just close the door to your bedroom for 15 minutes. Even the most social of us need time to recenter ourselves. If this is something you struggle with, check out these <a href="https://bemorewithless.com/no/" target="_blank" >,<u>10 simple ways to help you say no</u></a>.</p>
<h6><strong>One In, One Out</strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_b6f64bb7d8aa4736b6fc2d1e6699cd09~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="The name of the rule says it all, “one in, one out.”" alt="A woman peruses her closet."></figure><p>A few weeks ago, we went through our<a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/getting-staying-organized-for-the-new-year" target="_blank" > ,<u>Stax Method of Getting & Staying Organized</u></a> for the New Year, and we are so proud of the great work you all did getting started! But, let’s not stop now!</p>

<p><strong>The easiest way to be organized is to stay organized</strong>. So, to keep our organization on track for 2022, don’t forget the one in, one out rule.</p>

<p>For each thing you add to your closet, choose something that you no longer use to donate or sell. We love our little black dresses too, but there is no reason we need nine of them hanging in our closet. If you haven’t used it in over a year, it’s a great contender for being donated. </p>
<h6><strong>Read a Book</strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_17ef1b66ab10440d9f723084621ba49a~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Snuggle up with a good book and reap many benefits." alt="A book left open on a bed with a pair of reading glasses."></figure><p>Reading isn’t just good for your mind. It’s good for your soul. A good book can teleport you to another world. It gets your creativity pumping, forces you to use your brain, and improves communication. The things we can learn from books are all-encompassing, from general knowledge to compassion to communication skills. </p>

<p>A good book is an essential part of our self-care habits. Grab one of your Stax instructor’s favorites for the season, snuggle up on the couch, and get a good read in.</p><ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/40097951-the-silent-patient?ac=1&#38;from_search=true&#38;qid=9XwS1KEJDC&#38;rank=1" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>The Silent Patient</u></strong></a><strong> by Alex Michaelides: </strong>A psychological thriller about Alicia Berenson, an artist who shockingly shot her husband, and Theo Faber, a criminal psychotherapist who is trying to get to the bottom of this violent murder.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24611623-in-order-to-live?from_search=true&#38;from_srp=true&#38;qid=jITKWQJcvn&#38;rank=1" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>In Order to Live</u></strong></a><strong> by Yeonmi Park: </strong>The autobiography of human rights activist and North Korean defectorYeonmi Park, who tells the story of her long and difficult journey to freedom.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54404602-the-sweetness-of-water?ac=1&#38;from_search=true&#38;qid=M3kl1l9xhm&#38;rank=1" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>The Sweetness of Water</u></strong></a><strong> by Nathan Harris: </strong>A novel that dives into the complexities of the relationship between two freedmen and the farmer they work with during the end of the Civil War.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/36809135-where-the-crawdads-sing?ac=1&#38;from_search=true&#38;qid=WM9fH72uiX&#38;rank=1" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>Where the Crawdads Sing</u></strong></a><strong> by Delia Owens: </strong>After growing up isolated and learning from the land, Kya becomes interested in two young men from town. This coming-of-age story contemplates how isolation can influence us.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/21853621-the-nightingale?ac=1&#38;from_search=true&#38;qid=pk6Q6V66ai&#38;rank=1" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>The Nightingale</u></strong></a><strong> by Kristin Hannah: </strong>This best seller is about two sisters in France during World War II and is filled with plot twists that will continuously pull on your heartstrings.</li>
</ul><h6><strong>Go Internet-Lite</strong></h6><p>It’s so hard to go offline in 2022. Between home office, screens everywhere, and the rolling lockdowns, sometimes it’s just easier to stay glued to your device. Screen time rates have risen drastically due to the pandemic, and it’s hurting us both mentally and physically. </p>

<p>According to<a href="https://www.scripps.org/news_items/6626-how-much-screen-time-is-too-much" target="_blank" > ,<u>Scripps</u></a>, too much screen time leads to eye strain, headaches, disruptions in our sleep patterns, pain in the neck, shoulder, and back, tendonitis, carpal tunnel, and even social media addiction.</p>

<p>Looking for a way to break your toxic social media additions? </p><ol>
  <li>Turn your phone to grayscale</li>
  <li>Turn off your notifications</li>
  <li>Uninstall all but the most essential apps (we’re not looking at you, Instagram)</li>
  <li>Use time tracking tools to limit usage</li>
</ol><p>According to former<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/grayscale-ios-android-smartphone-addiction/" target="_blank" > ,<u>Google design ethicist Tristan Harris</u></a>, going grayscale removes positive reinforcements and dampens the urge to keep loading up social media feeds or games.</p>

<p>Get off your phone and spend more time with some of the other healthy habits on this list.</p>
<h6><strong>Be Grateful</strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_d0a95281251a4796bbe4e4ab936a38ef~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Practice gratitude with a daily journal entry." alt="“Today I Am Grateful,” a gratitude journal."></figure><p>Unfortunately, the world has a lot of negative things going on right now that it’s easy to focus on what we don’t have or can’t do, rather than being grateful for what we do have and can do. By practicing gratitude in our daily lives, we can totally switch our mindset and our energy into a more positive light.</p>

<p>One way to help us focus on gratitude is by journaling. Journaling is a great addition to a healthy morning or bedtime routine. If you’re struggling to find things to be grateful about in your life, check out <a href="https://www.gaiam.com/blogs/discover/8-reasons-to-be-grateful" target="_blank" >,<u>Gaiam’s 8 Reasons to be Grateful</u></a> for some inspiration.</p>
<h6><strong>Take Your Supplements </strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_9ad743b1f8a743b698775fd240561313~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="The right nutrients will keep your body feeling its best this winter." alt="Delicious and healthy foods full of magnesium."></figure><p>During the winter, we face many more attacks on our immune system, and now with Covid, it’s more important than ever that we take care of our bodies and keep them ready to fight off any infections. Not only that, but we tend to feel sluggish and sad in the winter as well.</p>

<p>Last month, we rounded up a list of the <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/best-supplements-for-winter-to-improve-your-energy-immunity-recovery" target="_blank" >,<u>Best Supplements for Winter to Improve Your Energy, Immunity, and Recovery</u></a>. These all-natural additions to your diet can help your body combat the winter blues and keep your serotonin and melatonin levels up.</p>
<h6><strong>Move Your Body</strong></h6><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_88037baf2d354907b0faeea64a2701bb~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Your favorite STAX trainers will help you keep your body moving this winter!" alt="One of our favorite STAX trainers is ready to train you through a cycle class."></figure><p>You already know that we’re here to help you with this one! It is so easy to get complacent in the winter, with the cold weather, and endless holidays. But it is so much easier to fall out of shape than to get back into it, so now is not the time to let all your handwork fall to the wayside! </p>

<p>Between our strength and spin classes that are available both <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/on-demand" target="_blank" ><u>online</u></a> and in-studio, we’ve got enough content and classes available to you that you’ll never get bored. Both strength training and cardio have positive effects on your mental and physical health, so exercise should always be on your to-do list for self-care.</p> <h6><strong>Throw Away Your Scale</strong></h6>
<p>We have been taught from a young age that what we read on the scale is somehow a reflection of us. That's a lie. You are so much more than a number.</p>

<p><strong>Throw that dang scale in the garbage!</strong> Weighing yourself daily can be damaging to your mental health. Our weight isn’t always a good representation of our physical health anyway.</p>

<p>If you’re feeding your body the healthy food and nutrition that it needs and getting plenty of exercise, who cares what your exact weight is. This year, focus on how you feel on the inside and not on what the scale reads back to you.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Stax Your Way Back on Track]]></title><description><![CDATA[Stax Cycle Club has stackable strength training videos and cardio spin classes for you to start your new year right.]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/stax-your-way-back-on-track</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61e83472f3435e0016d87cae</guid><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[strength training]]></category><category><![CDATA[cardiovascular training]]></category><category><![CDATA[cardio]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 19:26:59 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_314985f57b184952aef04b132218368d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last month, we treated ourselves with kindness, indulged in some <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/treat-yo-elf-healthy-holiday-treats" target="_blank" ><u>holiday treats</u></a>, and gave ourselves extra time to spend with our loved ones. Now, it’s a new year, and we can continue this trend of being kind to ourselves as we work to find our way back to our healthy habits and even create some new ones along the way.</p>

<p>After ringing in 2022, now is the perfect time to tackle hit up our top viewed <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/2021wrapped" target="_blank" ><u>favorite classes from 2021</u></a>! With a huge selection of Stax classes to choose from, you can try something new each day. Alternate between strength training and cardio for a complete fitness overhaul and start the new year right.</p>
<h2><strong>Unlimited Benefits with Strength Training</strong></h2>
<p>Many people focus on strength training to make them look more toned, but what we really love about strength training is all of the health benefits that come along with it. You won’t just look better, you’ll feel better, and you’ll get stronger - we don’t need any help opening up that pickle jar this year!</p>

<p>On top of increasing muscle mass, strength training:</p><ul>
  <li>Improves our flexibility and mobility</li>
  <li>Increases bone density</li>
  <li>Helps maintain and increases our balance</li>
</ul><p>There are just as many mental benefits as well, like higher self-esteem and lower levels of depression or anxiety. Basically, strength training benefits your body, mind, and soul, so you don’t want to skip it!</p>
<h4><strong>Stax Sculpt Classes</strong></h4><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_a4519da965f94472bded488d69d03c83~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Hit one of our strength training courses for health benefits for the mind, body, and soul" alt="A pile of 3-pound weights in the STAX gym"></figure><p>With your <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/on-demand" target="_blank" ><u>Stax membership</u></a>, you have unlimited access to our live-streamed classes and our Sculpt Library, so you’ll never run out of fun and engaging strength training options. Our classes are built to be stacked, so you can dig deep and give your body exactly what it needs!</p>

<p>Start with an intense but short cardio warm-up to get your blood pumping and then stack on a full-body workout or target a specific area that you want to work on. Don’t forget a cool down at the end of your workout to bring your heart rate back to normal.</p>
<h4><strong>Warm-up:</strong></h4><p>To get your workout started, warm up with a quick and dirty cardio class combined with mobility. These warm-ups will get your heart rate pumping, bring blood flow to your muscles, and loosen up your joints, preventing injury and post-workout muscle soreness.</p> <h4><strong>Full Body Stacks with Janelle:</strong></h4><p>If you want to get the most bang for your buck and hit all the muscle groups at once, check out one of Janelle’s full-body stacks! Her positive, friendly energy is just the boost you need to push yourself through these intense workouts. You can focus on just one of these courses or add on a targeted course afterward.</p><ul>
  <li><strong>30 Min Full Body: </strong>Perfect for those trying to squeeze in a quick workout, this class defines and tones your body in only half an hour.</li>
  <li><strong>40 Min Full Body Barre: </strong>Work on toning and flexibility with a barre class that uses elements from ballet, yoga, and pilates.</li>
  <li><strong>30 Min Full Body Sculpt: </strong>If you’re already feeling strong but want to focus more on muscle definition, the full-body sculpt class will have your muscles burning.</li>
  <li><strong>40 Min Full Body: </strong>If you have a little extra time and want to hit it hard, this longer full-body workout with minimal equipment is exactly what you need.</li>
</ul> 
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_c62cab4e5e23425a9fb06d85cfad4c7d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Check out our 40 Min Full Body Barre Class" alt=" A woman works on her strength with a barre workout"></figure><p><strong>Targeted Stacks:</strong></p>
<p>Instead of working out the whole body, pick a day to target each muscle group individually. This gives you a super intense workout while allowing other muscle groups the proper time to recover. Sprinkle some cardio classes on the days in between!</p><ul>
  <li><strong>20 Min Booty & Core: </strong>Blast your booty and work your core with this intense double-targeted class.</li>
  <li><strong>10 Min Core: </strong>If you’re pressed for time, hit this quick core workout to strengthen your upper and lower abs and your obliques.</li>
  <li><strong>Upper Body Blast: </strong>This is the perfect targeted workout for your arms, shoulders, and back.</li>
  <li><strong>10 Min Pilates Core: </strong>Work your body and your mind while strengthening your body.</li>
  <li><strong>20 Min Arms & Abs: </strong>Focus on your upper body and your abs with this 20-minute intensive workout.</li>
  <li><strong>20 Min Arms & Core: </strong>Check out this class for an upper body and full core workout, including your back and obliques.</li>
</ul> <p><strong>Cool Down:</strong></p>
<p>Don’t forget how important cool downs are! A proper cool down is equally important for strength training and cardio, so stack on one of these classes at the end of every workout.</p><ul>
  <li><strong>5 or 7 Min Cool Down: </strong>This gradual recovery will help bring your heart rate and breathing back to a normal rate, plus help you relax a bit before going about your day.</li>
  <li><strong>9/10/12/15 Min Stretch: </strong>Don’t forget to get a good stretch in after your workout. You can choose however long you have to spare, but don’t skimp here! Stretching will prevent achy muscles and lower your chance of injury long term.</li>
</ul> <h2><strong>Spin Your Way to Success</strong></h2>
<p>We're sure that we aren’t the first people to tell you how important cardio is for your health. Aerobic exercise strengthens your heart and lungs, reduces your risk of many life-threatening diseases, and keeps your metabolism pumping. Just like strength training, cardio training releases endorphins which lower stress, anxiety, and depression. Not to mention, you’ll sleep like a baby!</p>

<p>We might be partial, but we think that spin classes are the number one way to get your cardio workouts in. Since cycling is low-impact, it’s great for those who need a workout that is gentle on the joints. It strengthens your lower body and core while giving you a powerful cardio workout. Plus, indoor cycling can be modified to a variety of intensities, so it’s absolutely perfect for all levels!</p>
<h4><strong>Stax Spin Classes</strong></h4><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_1b0aac3ad7154d9cad07a84c37a5c76a~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Our spin classes will have your heart pumping!" alt="A STAX instructor motivates her spin class"></figure><p>At Stax, our classes deliver not only a hardcore workout but a fun, self-empowering environment that will have you feeling like your most badass self in no time! There are hundreds of full or express spin classes available with our rockstar team of instructors. We guarantee you won’t ever get bored here!</p> <p><strong>Full Spin Classes:</strong></p>
<p>Real, raw, and unrehearsed collection of our signature 50- and 60-minute spin classes. We can promise you two things: you WILL sweat and it WILL be worth it!</p><ul>
  <li><strong>45 Minute Turn & Burn: </strong>Your muscles will definitely feel the burn with high-speed cycle class.</li>
  <li><strong>Stax 40 Minute Endurance: </strong>See how far you can go with this hardcore 40-minute endurance course.</li>
  <li><strong>Stax 50 Minute Endurance: </strong>If 40-minutes isn’t enough for you, push yourself further with this 50 minutes race to the finish.</li>
  <li><strong>40 Minute Dark & Stormy: </strong>Don’t be afraid - this dark and stormy cycle ride will leave you feeling invigorated and refreshed.</li>
  <li><strong>40 Minute Beyonce & Booty: </strong>Bless your booty and your ears while jamming to Queen Bey.</li>
</ul> 
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_84519b546cb74da1afe42be3cff4b68a~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="This intense express class gives you a combo and strength and conditioning in one" alt="A STAX class involving both spin and arm strength training"></figure><p><strong>Express Content:</strong></p>
<p>Don't short yourself, even if you're short on time. We have express spin cycle workouts that you can squeeze into your busy day. </p><ul>
  <li><strong>20 or 30 Minute HIIT: </strong>Pick your poison. Our 20 or 30-minute high-intensity workout will handle your cardio and strength training for the day.</li>
  <li><strong>30 Minute Express: </strong>If you’re in a hurry, choose this quick 30 minute express spin class to get your workout in while you can.</li>
  <li><strong>35 Minute HIIT & Arms: </strong>While this course is quick, it still packs quite the punch. This high-intensity interval training knocks out cardio and arm strengthening at the same time.</li>
</ul> <p>Are you ready to get back on track? Get our <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/change-season" target="_blank" ><u>ten-day reset challenge</u></a> and come back to it again and again. </p>

<p>Ready to #MISBEHAVE? Try our Stax on-demand platform and get access to real, unrehearsed workout videos and other bonus content. You can try it for free to get the fire burning. </p> ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Holiday Guide to Gifts for Spin Class Lovers]]></title><description><![CDATA[Have you been naughty or nice? We’ve got the best, all-inclusive guide for the perfect holiday gifts for spin class lovers!  ]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/holiday-guide-to-gifts-for-spin-class-lovers</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61a653fe23326800161a9631</guid><category><![CDATA[fitness equipment]]></category><category><![CDATA[strength training]]></category><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 02:32:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_06a8e768715a4b3aa1550b263f2f99d8~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The holiday season is upon us folks! Nothing beats watching someone we love unwrap the perfect gift that we chose for them. If you’re looking for the ideal present for your favorite Stax member or spin class lover, look no further! We’ve got the best, all-inclusive guide for the perfect holiday gifts for spin cycle enthusiasts.  </p>
<h2><strong>How to Choose Great Gifts for Spin Class Lovers</strong></h2><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_5696d97ee5384608835b01cad77b0f4e~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="These great gifts for spin class lovers  will have your loved ones grinning from ear to ear." alt="Woman with pig tails and sunglasses smiling and giving peace fingers"></figure><p>Some of the most obvious things that spin-lovers need on a day-to-day basis can be a bit too personal to pick out. Gifts like spin shoes or clothing may be stressful to choose because everyone has a unique style and sizing can be personal. Luckily we have tons of other great gifts for spin class lovers that will have your loved ones grinning from ear to ear.</p>
<h3><strong>New Spin Bike</strong></h3>
<p>If you really want to impress someone and go all out on a holiday gift this year, there is nothing like a brand new spin bike. While it might be a little hard to wrap, your loved one will be totally giddy to find their very own spin bike under the tree this year!</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_d620b5cf0b1441ebbd0f07f246b726df~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="The ultimate gift for the holidays: a new spin bike" alt="Woman laying across a Stages SC3 indoor spin bike"></figure><p>Our favorite is the <a href="https://dotmarfitness.com/collections/indoor-cycle/products/stages-sc3-cycle-bike" target="_blank" >,<u>Stages SC3</u></a>, the model we ride at Stax, or the <a href="https://dotmarfitness.com/collections/indoor-cycle/products/stages-sc1-cycle-bike" target="_blank" >,<u>Stages SC1</u></a>. These bikes will take anyone’s at-home cycle studio to the next level. The Stages SC3 can connect to all of your technology wirelessly and will take the guesswork out of training. It keeps you on track with your fitness goals by using the most accurate performance measures out there.</p>

<p><strong>Our friends at </strong><a href="https://dotmarfitness.com/" target="_blank" ><strong><u>Dotmar Fitness</u></strong></a><strong> are offering Stax members free shipping for all Stages bikes & accessories (promo code "Staxcycle").</strong></p>

<p>As much as we love this bike, the price point isn’t for everyone. Check out our list of the <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/5-best-spin-bikes-for-home" target="_blank" >,<u>best spin bikes for your home</u></a> to see some more economical choices as well.</p>
<h3><strong>Resistance Bands For Sculpt Classes</strong></h3>
<p>All of our Stax members have definitely heard us raving about resistance bands lately. These workout accessories increase resistance for a variety of different exercises, help you burn more, and get stronger faster! They’re one of the best gifts for spin class lovers.</p> <p>Resistance bands are super convenient and versatile because you can use them on their own, during a spin session, or even on the go. They’re easy to bring with you no matter where you’re going, so you can always sneak in a workout. </p>

<p>We love the<a href="https://www.amazon.com/UPOWEX-Resistance-Whatafit-Exercise-Training/dp/B07DWSPQQY/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?dchild=1&#38;keywords=resistance+bands+set&#38;qid=1631807628&#38;sr=8-1-spons&#38;psc=1&#38;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEzOFFIT1A3SUhXTTRBJmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwOTgyODAwV0ZOWlM0U1kxR0lRJmVuY3J5cHRlZEFkSWQ9QTAzMTQ0NzUzMjg5UFNPODNaNzNNJndpZGdldE5hbWU9c3BfYXRmJmFjdGlvbj1jbGlja1JlZGlyZWN0JmRvTm90TG9nQ2xpY2s9dHJ1ZQ==" target="_blank" > ,<u>Whatafit Resistance Band Set</u></a> which would make the perfect holiday gift. It comes with everything you need to get started working with resistance bands, like two handles, two ankle attachments, a door anchor, and a variety of bands with different resistances. It even comes with a convenient bag to carry everything. That means your loved one can bring them to their Stax classes!</p>

<p>Check out our <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/our-favorite-resistance-bands-how-to-use-them" target="_blank" >,<u>resistance band post</u></a> for more information on how to use them and for some other options for resistance band presents.</p>
<h3><strong>Stax Swag</strong></h3>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/undefined"></figure><p>Get your loved one some of the freshest Stax merch so they can be decked out head to toe at their Stax classes. Clothes can be hard to pick out but you can’t go wrong with any of our stylish workout clothes. We have a tank, jogger, crop top, and even an entire leopard collection, plus a branded Stax hat and workout tights.</p>

<p>Check out all of the <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/swag" target="_blank" >,<u>Stax gear</u></a>, they make great gifts for spin class lovers.</p>
<h3><strong>The Best Spin Class Accessories</strong></h3>
<p>Looking for stocking stuffers or other small gifts? There are tons of brilliant accessories that would be perfect for the spin fanatic in your life. We covered quite a few fun accessories in our article about the best<a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/6-genius-tiktok-fitness-hacks-you-wish-you-d-known-about-sooner" target="_blank" > ,<u>TikTok Fitness Hacks</u></a>. Here are a few of our favorites for this holiday season!</p>
<h4><strong>Massagers</strong></h4>
<p>They will no doubt be feeling sore after some of our more intense Stax classes. Help them loosen up with an at-home massager they can use on themselves. You can choose between<a href="https://www.amazon.com/AmazonBasics-High-Density-Round-Roller-18-inches/dp/B00XM2MXK8/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?keywords=foam+rollers&#38;qid=1638233469&#38;sr=8-1-spons&#38;psc=1&#38;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEzSDFPOE02WEY5S0RKJmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwMjYzNjg3M1Q2MzhIRDhDVjVFUiZlbmNyeXB0ZWRBZElkPUEwNjA4NDUyWlgxTVFJRUJMUDExJndpZGdldE5hbWU9c3BfYXRmJmFjdGlvbj1jbGlja1JlZGlyZWN0JmRvTm90TG9nQ2xpY2s9dHJ1ZQ==" target="_blank" > ,<u>foam rollers</u></a>,<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kieba-Massage-Lacrosse-Myofascial-Therapy/dp/B017V7UKW2/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?keywords=massage+balls&#38;qid=1638233415&#38;s=hpc&#38;sr=1-1-spons&#38;psc=1&#38;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUFURlBHRE01TU43U1UmZW5jcnlwdGVkSWQ9QTAwODM4NzIzQThUWVJDOEQxTkM0JmVuY3J5cHRlZEFkSWQ9QTA1MjI1NDYxUU1RR0ZPVk1YTENKJndpZGdldE5hbWU9c3BfYXRmJmFjdGlvbj1jbGlja1JlZGlyZWN0JmRvTm90TG9nQ2xpY2s9dHJ1ZQ==" target="_blank" > ,<u>massage balls</u></a>,<a href="https://www.amazon.com/TriggerPoint-MobiPoint-Textured-Massage-Targeted/dp/B01LX72D9A/ref=sr_1_3_sspa?keywords=trigger+point+massage+ball&#38;qid=1638233437&#38;s=hpc&#38;sr=1-3-spons&#38;psc=1&#38;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEzUEFPTzVQVkxENktFJmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwOTI1MzY3MUNaTDNaQ0NDNU1ROCZlbmNyeXB0ZWRBZElkPUEwODQ3MTU3MkNUTDNGSEVORUlBTiZ3aWRnZXROYW1lPXNwX2F0ZiZhY3Rpb249Y2xpY2tSZWRpcmVjdCZkb05vdExvZ0NsaWNrPXRydWU=" target="_blank" > ,<u>spiky massage balls</u></a>, or even<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B089Q6FYW2/ref=sspa_dk_detail_1?psc=1&#38;pd_rd_i=B089Q6FYW2&#38;pd_rd_w=HpRwF&#38;pf_rd_p=887084a2-5c34-4113-a4f8-b7947847c308&#38;pd_rd_wg=CJRFj&#38;pf_rd_r=GQTG9V539ARX8T3A2K5N&#38;pd_rd_r=f4384f33-60f3-4be5-8b98-fb34f61f03be&#38;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEyRTdGWEhXVUZYSDFJJmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwNTQzODExMUVPRVhFM0pUMTZSNiZlbmNyeXB0ZWRBZElkPUEwNTc0ODA3Mkc5OUtTVUNQSzdXOCZ3aWRnZXROYW1lPXNwX2RldGFpbCZhY3Rpb249Y2xpY2tSZWRpcmVjdCZkb05vdExvZ0NsaWNrPXRydWU=" target="_blank" > ,<u>massage guns</u></a>. We love this<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Posture-Magic-Massage-Myofascial-Trigger/dp/B081SBP698/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?keywords=trigger+point+massage+ball&#38;qid=1638233500&#38;s=hpc&#38;sr=1-1-spons&#38;psc=1&#38;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEyWkFOOE42MERUTllXJmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwMjIxMzY3MzU3WVRTM1dCNTI5SiZlbmNyeXB0ZWRBZElkPUEwNzc4MDcxMzVMN0dBVFdGN0RFTSZ3aWRnZXROYW1lPXNwX2F0ZiZhY3Rpb249Y2xpY2tSZWRpcmVjdCZkb05vdExvZ0NsaWNrPXRydWU=" target="_blank" > ,<u>set</u></a> that has a little bit of everything. </p>
<h4><strong>Gift Cards</strong></h4>
<p>On a similar note, if they would prefer a professional massage, you could get them a gift card for a relaxing 90-minute session with a licensed masseuse. Other repairing and healing services for workout fanatics are growing more popular too. Think about gift cards for cryotherapy, cupping, or saunas, all of which would make a great gift for the athlete on your list.</p>
<h4><strong>Portable Projector</strong></h4>
<p>Make your own virtual studio in the comfort of your own home with a portable projector. Instead of trying to balance your phone or tablet on your handlebars or building a tower to sit your laptop on, project your favorite spin or sculpting classes on the big screen! </p>

<p>Our Stax squad loves this <a href="https://apemans.com/products/apeman-m4-mini-portable-projector" target="_blank" ><u>mini portable projector</u></a> for rocking out to their favorite classes.</p>
<h4><strong>Water Bottles</strong></h4>
<p>Amazon has a never-ending collection of fun water bottles or cups that will fit anyone’s style. Whether you’re looking for something<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Christmas-Friends-Coworkers-Double-Insulated-Tumblers/dp/B08LBM3NTM/ref=sr_1_3?keywords=christmas+water+bottle&#38;qid=1638234404&#38;sr=8-3" target="_blank" > ,<u>holiday-themed</u></a>,<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Free-Reusable-Water-Bottle-Marker/dp/B07MFZC7XB/ref=sr_1_5?keywords=silly+water+bottle&#38;qid=1638234154&#38;sr=8-5" target="_blank" > ,<u>silly</u></a>,<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Water-Bottle-Time-Marker-Motivational/dp/B081J96GSW/ref=sr_1_10?keywords=edgy+water+bottle&#38;qid=1638234173&#38;sr=8-10" target="_blank" > ,<u>aesthetic</u></a>, or<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Hydro-Flask-Water-Bottle-Straw/dp/B08TL135FY/ref=sr_1_8?keywords=water+bottle&#38;qid=1638234238&#38;sr=8-8" target="_blank" > ,<u>plain Jane</u></a>, there is a water bottle to complement everyone’s personality.</p>
<h4><strong>Hair Accessories</strong></h4>
<p>The ladies who love to hit spin class often struggle with trying to keep their hair looking good post-workout. Dry shampoo is a great stocking stuffer that will help her keep her hair looking fresh after spin class. You can’t go wrong with <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Batiste-Shampoo-Original-Fragrance-6-35/dp/B07MGZ6X2Q/ref=zg_bs_10656664011_2?_encoding=UTF8&#38;refRID=C8AQX3T3MY5C2ARTTQ0S&#38;th=1" target="_blank" >,<u>Batiste</u></a>! Other great hair accessories you could get for them are hair scrunchies. Scrunchies are fun because you can go neutral or funky to bring some flair to their workout outfit. Plus they don’t crease your hair like regular elastics. You can get a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Whaline-Scrunchies-Elastics-Scrunchy-Bobbles/dp/B075M76F8L/ref=sr_1_11?keywords=scrunchies&#38;qid=1638234693&#38;s=beauty&#38;sr=1-11" target="_blank" >,<u>variety pack</u></a><u> </u>for tons of options.</p>
<h3><strong>Stax Gift Card or Annual Membership</strong></h3>
<p>If you’re still at a loss for what to get your spin class fan for the holidays or you’re simply out of time and need something ASAP, you can look into a <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/gift-card" target="_blank" ><u>Stax gift card</u></a>! Give the gift of fitness with on-demand spin and sculpting classes at Stax. This is truly the gift that keeps on giving!</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_9dfafde2336145c198e3136856fdefab~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_742,h_417,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Naughty or nice, it's time to #MISBEHAVE. See you in the studio! </p>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Treat Yo’ Elf! Healthy Holiday Treats]]></title><description><![CDATA[Keep up your healthy routine this holiday season with help from your Stax fam! We've got healthy holiday treats just for you!]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/treat-yo-elf-healthy-holiday-treats</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61b296b225abc70016535695</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[nutrition]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy eating]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy habits]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 16:42:23 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_612bb0773e504fc78990518410f00337~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Happy Holidays Fam!</p>

<p>Spending time with those we love seems to go hand in hand with indulging more in sweets and adult beverages. The great thing is, we believe a healthy balanced lifestyle over the holidays involves a little bit of movement and indulging in all the holiday sweets and festive bevvies.</p>

<p>This week, Lindsay and Joelle joined Emily to share some of their favorite ways to turn holiday indulgences into healthy snacks, as well as improve our mindset around what it means to "treat ourselves". </p>
 
<h2>Find Your Equilibrium This Holiday Season</h2>
<p>Stax is all about balance and that's why we encourage taking part in all the festive fun that comes with the holiday season. </p>
<h3><strong>Ho, Ho, Hold Up! Don’t Beat Yourself Up!</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_a8bc6f1325f444e8a3925324490ed0fc~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Don't forget to enjoy life!" alt="Hey don't worry, just live"></figure><p>We only get one life to live, and there is no shame in treating yourself to foods that bring you joy during the holiday season! Drink the eggnog, eat the cheesecake, have the beer, devour the chocolate (<a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/our-top-10-superfoods-list-for-you-freebie" target="_blank" ><u>cacao</u></a> is a superfood). The key here is moderation.  We believe in mindful eating, and being aware which foods make us feel energized and nourished.</p>

<p>Be kind to yourself. If you get a little bit off track after your company’s Christmas party or a big family meal, don’t beat yourself up. Balance your indulgences by getting back on track the next day.</p>
<h3><strong>Hack Your Holiday</strong></h3>
<p>All that being said, there is absolutely no reason we can’t carry some good habits with us into the season. Especially with the recipes we’ve got coming at you! You don’t have to sacrifice flavor or joy with these fun holiday snacks.</p>

<p>We’re here to hack your holiday and keep it healthy - if that’s what you want! Here are some of our favorite holiday hacks - perfect to bring to your next holiday party or potluck!</p>
<h2><strong>Healthy Holiday Treats</strong></h2><p>If you’re in charge of bringing a dish for a potluck or party, try one of these healthy recipes that we love! Your body and your friends will appreciate it.</p>
<h3><strong>Healthy Hot Chocolate</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_d6753fa6cdf848378810f7a0f8eeac95~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Rich, creamy hot chocolate without the guilt" alt="Healthy hot chocolate"></figure><p>This homemade hot chocolate recipe is not only divine but also versatile. You can mix it up with whichever milk you prefer, plant-based or otherwise. Oat milk gives you a nice, thick hot chocolate or you can add a splash of whipping cream making it super creamy. The key ingredient here is the honey or maple syrup which will give it that sweet taste we’re craving.
</p>
<p>Once you’ve whipped up this easy hot chocolate, you can add some extras to it as well. Pour in some espresso for a healthy, homemade mocha, or if you need to take the edge off, add a shot of Bailey’s.</p>
<h4><strong>Ingredients:</strong></h4><ul>
  <li>2 cups plant-based milk of your choice</li>
  <li>2 tbsp of cocoa powder</li>
  <li>2 tbsp of honey or maple syrup</li>
  <li>1 tsp of vanilla extract</li>
  <li>Pinch of cinnamon</li>
  <li>Optional add-ins:<ul>
  <li>splash of whipping cream for richness</li>
  <li>a handful of chocolate chips</li>
  <li>top with marshmallows</li>
</ul></li>
</ul><h4><strong>Instructions:</strong></h4><p>Mix all the ingredients together in a saucepan over medium heat until it comes to a boil. Whisk the mixture until it’s smooth and the texture is rich and creamy! Easy peasy!</p>
<h3><strong>Little Santa Fruit Kabobs</strong></h3>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/85bcec_c72ed5ec867e421c8deb590be7078ba0~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>If you’re looking for a holiday snack that requires absolutely zero cooking, you’re in luck! These little Santas are so cute you almost don’t want to eat them and they could not be any easier to make. 
</p>
<p>You can get all the ingredients you need in one section at the grocery store for under 10 bucks. Everyone will be so excited to try these little snacks. Bring them to a holiday potluck to impress your friends or to a kid’s party and be dubbed the “cool mom.”</p>
<h4><strong>Ingredients:</strong></h4><ul>
  <li>Strawberries</li>
  <li>Green grapes</li>
  <li>Banana slices</li>
  <li>Mini marshmallows</li>
</ul><h4><strong>Instructions:</strong></h4><p>Slice your bananas and cut the greens off of the strawberries. Push a toothpick halfway through your grape, then slide on the banana, strawberry, and last, the mini marshmallow. You can prepare a whole platter ahead of time for a super simple yet healthy holiday snack!</p>
<h3><strong>Chocolate Coconut Protein Snowballs</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_b2acc01c30044821b2bed4dfd17f0e5b~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="The perfect post-workout holiday treat!" alt="Chocolate Coconut Protein Snowballs"></figure><p>These scrumptious fudge balls are just as good for you as they are delicious. The holiday treats are one of Joelle’s favorite recipes from <a href="https://michellemcgrattan.com/" target="_blank" >Michelle McGrattan</a> and they pack the perfect combination of fat, protein, and carbs for a tasty, post-workout snack. They take a little bit more preparation but are still super fast and simple.
</p>
<p>You can make some changes here to suit your taste buds! Try coconut or almond flour if you don’t have oat. This version tastes just like a brownie but you can switch it up to a vanilla protein powder for a different taste altogether. Make sure to use a vegan protein powder as whey protein doesn’t work quite right. 
</p><h4><strong>Ingredients:</strong></h4><ul>
  <li>1 cup Medjool dates, pitted</li>
  <li>1/7 cup cocoa powder</li>
  <li>1/4 cup plant-based chocolate protein powder</li>
  <li>1/4 cup organic raw honey</li>
  <li>1 cup unsweetened shredded coconut (more for rolling)</li>
  <li>1/4 cup oat flour</li>
  <li>1 tsp vanilla extract</li>
  <li>1/2 cup unsalted cashews</li>
</ul><h4><strong>Instructions:</strong></h4><p>Place all of the ingredients in a food processor and blend until the mixture pulls together. Roll into balls with slightly damp hands. Cover the balls in shredded coconut. Voila! You can store them in the fridge or freezer until you’re ready to enjoy.</p>
<h2><strong>Eat, Drink, and Be Merry</strong></h2><p>This is the season to focus on family and friends and enjoy yourself. After all, it is the most wonderful time of the year. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_603722ef58854617ab4088f9881025ea~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Enjoy the holiday season to the fullest!" alt="Two ladies enjoying a holiday pajama party"></figure><p>Instead of focusing on what you can’t or shouldn’t have, focus on these delightful, guilt-free holiday treats that everyone can enjoy. </p>

<p>Then, when you do encounter that irresistible cookie or have one glass of wine too many, no worries (<a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/best-supplements-for-winter-to-improve-your-energy-immunity-recovery" target="_blank" ><u>we have your hangover cure</u></a>)! Have your fun and then take care of yourself the next day. Get a good night’s rest, drink lots of water, and come join us for a <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/on-demand" target="_blank" ><u>spin class</u></a>. Your body will love you for it!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Stax Method of Getting &#38; Staying Organized for the New Year]]></title><description><![CDATA[Need a little organization in your life? We have got you covered with all the tips and tricks to getting &#38; staying organized!]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/getting-staying-organized-for-the-new-year</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61aa9545098e9e001615cafb</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[mindset]]></category><category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category><category><![CDATA[organization tips]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 20:04:15 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_c49d13cbb4ff423f92c3d68c1e3d77db~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_800,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the holidays coming up you might notice your schedule is even more jam-packed than usual. This time of the year is meant to be for spending time with family and relaxing, not stressing out! By adopting a little more discipline in your everyday habits and getting more organized, you can actually give yourself <em>more</em> freedom and mental clarity and gift yourself with a sense of peace and calm.</p>

<p>Emily got together with Janelle and Mel G., two of our Stax trainers who have their lives organized to a T. The crew hosted an Instagram Live at <a href="https://www.instagram.com/staxcycleclub/" target="_blank" >,<u>@staxcycleclub</u></a> to give you the scoop on some simple tips on how to get organized this holiday season.</p> 
<h2><strong>Organizational Tips to Get You Started</strong></h2>
<p>Janelle is one of our Stax sculpt class instructors while Mel G. teaches spin classes. Both of these ladies live for all things organization - from their homes to their exercise wardrobe to their schedules. They love living full lives and believe that by creating a clear and organized space they can tackle their busy schedules more gracefully. Check out their recommendations on how you can do the same!</p>
<h3><strong>Start Small</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_103a884fbb1443069a45e683dcc343ad~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_800,h_533,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Instead of trying to tackle your entire home, pick one small area that needs attention." alt="Plastic organizers for your bathroom drawer"></figure><p>Trying to get your life 100% organized when you’re starting from scratch can be so overwhelming, not to mention potentially setting you up for failure. <strong>Instead of trying to tackle your entire home, pick one small area that needs attention.</strong> Whether it’s your junk draw, your shoe closet, or your makeup vanity, start with one space at a time.</p>

<p>The key to organizing, especially with the smaller things, is to make sure everything has a home. Sort like with like. There are tons of organizational tools you can use like draw dividers or clear containers. Make sure everything has its own place.</p>

<p>Our ladies recommend trying to master one place for 30 days. If everything goes well, give yourself kudos! Now you will totally feel confident to tackle the next cluttered area in your house.</p>
<h3><strong>Find What Works for You</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_c49d13cbb4ff423f92c3d68c1e3d77db~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_800,h_534,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Being organized can support your wellness routine." alt="Clothes organized in a drawer using drawer inserts"></figure><p>We’re all a little bit different. Our homes are designed differently. We use different things on a daily basis and different things are important to us. That means there is no one size fits all solution to organization. You can use tips and tricks that you learn from others, but the key is finding what works best for you.</p>

<p>Being organized can totally support your wellness routine. When everything is at-the-ready for your post-workout shake, you’re much more likely to have it. When you’re sports bras and leggings are neatly where they belong, it’s much easier to get to the gym. <strong>Your organization solutions need to be easily accessible to make it functional and to make your life easier.</strong></p>

<p>Not only do you need to find a home for everything, but you need to make sure it’s the right home. If you like to read in bed, maybe the best place to organize your books is on your nightstand, not in the living room. If you never remember to take your vitamins with breakfast, try storing them next to your toothbrush instead. You don’t have to follow along with what works for other people. What’s important is what works for you.</p>
<h3><strong>Go Easy On Yourself</strong></h3>
<p>We’re always hard on ourselves, but organizing is supposed to help us feel more at peace - not stress us out even more.</p>

<p><strong>Treat yourself with grace on your organization journey.</strong> Even the seasoned pros occasionally find that things get a bit disheveled. If it gets a little messed up, just go back and reset it. By being flexible, you’ll be able to get yourself back on track instead of spiraling out of control. </p>

<p>Work on building positive habits instead of focusing on perfection.</p>
<h2><strong>Areas to Focus on</strong></h2>
<p>Ready to get organized? Here's where to start!</p><h3><strong>Organize Your Schedule</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_6ecbc000f6ef4349b4be9a47b4491f91~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_800,h_535,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Set yourself up for success by keeping a detailed schedule." alt="the iPhone calendar app"></figure><p>Being organized isn’t only limited to your physical objects. You can also get more organized with your schedule, especially for those of us who just can’t seem to find enough time in the day. Set yourself up for success by keeping a detailed schedule so you don’t miss a beat.</p>

<p>Most cell phones these days have a calendar app where you can schedule your days down to the hour. Don’t be afraid to schedule yourself time to complete “obvious” tasks like downtime for yourself or even time to organize your home.</p>

<p>You can not only link your calendar across all of your devices, but you can link up with your other family members too. This is especially helpful for busy parents juggling kids’ activities.</p>
<h3><strong>Organize Your Wardrobe</strong></h3><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_c144734e8bd64257b351c81a47d65cd5~mv2.jpeg/v1/fit/w_800,h_531,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Struggling to keep your closet organized? You're not alone!" alt="Organized clothes hanging on a rack"></figure><p>One of the hardest areas for many people to keep organized is their closet. If this is you, you're not alone! Luckily we have quite a few amazing wardrobe organization tips and tricks to help you clear the clutter out of your closet. Plus you can do some good for the environment and those in need.</p>

<p>One of the hardest things to do is make the decision to get rid of clothes. It can be really hard to say goodbye, especially when we have an emotional or sentimental attachment to an item. But donating your clothes or even selling them at a consignment shop is also a really great feeling. Here are a few ways to help give yourself a nudge in the right direction.</p>
<h4><strong>The One-In-One-Out Method</strong></h4>
<p>Just like it sounds, with this method, as soon as you add something new to your closet, you <em>have</em> to choose something to donate or sell. </p>

<p>If you buy some gorgeous new denim, then that pair of jeans you hardly wear anymore can be donated to a local woman’s shelter. If you snag a new workout set, that set on its last leg can be recycled into rags for cleaning.</p>
<h4><strong>The Reverse Hanger Trick</strong></h4>
<p>It’s the perfect time of the year to start this decluttering hack.</p><ul>
  <li>Go into your closet and flip all of your hangers, and put them back so the open end is out.</li>
  <li>Throughout the year, when you wear something, put it back on the hanger the normal way around.</li>
  <li>In six months or a year from now, you can go back and see which items you haven’t touched.</li>
</ul><p>If it’s been a year since you’ve even looked at that dress you still have from 2009, then it’s probably time to say goodbye.</p>
<h4><strong>Want Vs. Need</strong></h4>
<p>If we’re not paying attention, it can be hard to distinguish between a <em>want</em> versus a <em>need</em>. And we’re definitely not saying that you’re not allowed to have clothing that you want. Just being aware of the difference can really help you cut back on clutter and make the tough decision to say goodbye to something that’s no longer serving you.</p>

<p>We want to feel happy when we open our closets and see the pieces that we love, which is hard to do if you’ve accumulated too much.</p>
<h4><strong>find a clear + consistent home for your stuff</strong></h4>
<p>It's amazing how organized you can feel when you find a consistent way to store your clothes. Here's a simple way that Mel folds her sports bras, and organizes by level of support!</p>
<a href="https://video.wixstatic.com/video/85bcec_c2aa82ee4f3a44928bf9e04e8fbe5361/360p/mp4/file.mp4">https://video.wixstatic.com/video/85bcec_c2aa82ee4f3a44928bf9e04e8fbe5361/360p/mp4/file.mp4</a><h4><strong>Benefits of Recycling Clothing</strong></h4>
<p>Getting new things and ditching others doesn't have to be wasteful. It can be quite the opposite, in fact.</p>
<blockquote><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/brookerobertsislam/2021/10/01/fashion-is-overselling-circularity-and-recycling-but-there-is-hope/?sh=31f3b7665d95" target="_blank" >,<u>Fashion contributes</u></a> approximately 8% to global emissions, but as population and consumption grow, this figure is expected to increase by 45% come 2030.</blockquote>
<p>Recycling clothing, whether that’s by donating or selling it, is sustainable and can help others. When you resell your clothing via consignment shops, you’re helping the environment by passing an item on to someone else who can get more use out of it. If you donate the clothes, then you can aid those in need. Even items you think are totally done-zo like old raggedy towels can find good use in places like animal shelters.</p>
<h2><strong>Organization Products</strong></h2>
<p>You don’t have to spend a fortune on fancy products in order to get your house and your life organized. Many of Janelle’s organizational tools come from the dollar store or Amazon. Here are some of her favorites!</p><ul>
  <li><a href="https://lifewithpandj.ca/collections/amazon-favs/products/idesign-linus-plastic-adjustable-deep-in-drawer-dividers-for-storage-organization-utensils-kitchen-dresser-desk-bathroom-drawers-set-of-2-includes-4-pieces-clear" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>Adjustable Drawer Dividers</u></strong></a><strong>: </strong>These draw dividers are perfect to break up larger wardrobe drawers into smaller compartments for different things. Use them to separate your undies from your socks. Or, if you’re like Mel, your three different levels of sports bra support.</li>
  <li><a href="https://lifewithpandj.ca/collections/amazon-favs/products/command-cord-bundlers-grey-medium-2-bundlers-3-medium-strips" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>Command Cord Bundlers</u></strong></a><strong>: </strong>Unruly cords lying all over the place are so unsightly and make you feel disorganized even when you're not. Use these cord bundlers to get them off the floor and keep them organized and secure.</li>
  <li><a href="https://lifewithpandj.ca/collections/amazon-favs/products/adjustable-bamboo-drawer-dividers-organizers-large-expandable-utensil-organizer-separators-for-kitchen-dresser-bedroom-baby-drawer-bathroom-office-set-of-4-2-6-tall-17-5-22-inch-natural" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>Adjustable Bamboo Drawer Dividers</u></strong></a><strong>: </strong>These dividers are designed more for kitchen or bathroom drawers because of their lower height. You can use these to break up your junk drawer into more manageable sections or keep apart different kitchen utensils.</li>
  <li><a href="https://lifewithpandj.ca/collections/amazon-favs/products/tebery-4-ounce-capacity-glass-spice-jars-with-silver-metal-lids-shaker-tops-and-labels-set-of-18" target="_blank" >,<strong><u>Glass Spice Jars</u></strong></a><strong>: </strong>These spice jars are not only practical but also very aesthetically pleasing. Use these so that every time you open your spice drawer or cabinet, you feel excited to get cooking. Plus, you can save the planet by buying your spices in bulk instead of single-use plastic containers.</li>
</ul> 
<hr><p>By implementing these organizational tips and ideas into your daily routine and fine-tuning them so that they fit into your lifestyle and home, you’re going to improve your life in a big way.</p>

<p>It’s not about having a type A personality or being a control freak. It’s about setting yourself up for success as well as making your life easier and peaceful. Before you know it, all these things will become second nature and you’ll find yourself wondering how you ever lived without them. </p>

<p>Then you’ll be ready for the final boss level of organization: the label maker.</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Best Supplements for Winter to Improve Your Energy, Immunity &#38; Recovery]]></title><description><![CDATA[The best supplements to take during the winter to increase your energy, boost your immune system, and aid in recovery.]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/best-supplements-for-winter-to-improve-your-energy-immunity-recovery</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61a114b0d080210016a00ef5</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[nutrition]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy habits]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 16:48:33 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_b26d41b2f63d43ac8d04b710e94e6c2d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_877,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As we head into the winter, you may notice your energy lower, a decrease in your immunity (hello, cold and flu season), and have a harder time recovering from your workouts. To help counteract the winter blues, here are our top picks for supplements for winter! </p>

<p>If you missed it, Emily and Alex hosted a v fun Instagram Live session over at <a href="https://www.instagram.com/staxcycleclub/" target="_blank" ><u>@staxcycleclub</u></a> discussing the best supplements and vitamins that you should be taking. </p> <p>Alex Zilkie (<a href="https://www.instagram.com/alexzilkie/" target="_blank" ><u>@alexzilkie</u></a>) is a Stax instructor extraordinaire, <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/combining-fitness-and-pregnancy" target="_blank" ><u>mom</u></a>, medical professional, and certified nutrition coach. Here are her recommendations to keep you at the top of your game this season (even after too many bevies at your Christmas party). </p>
<h2>How the Winter Affects Your Mood</h2>
<p>You may have noticed that once the winter months come around, your mood and energy take a hit. You might start to feel sad, have low energy, have issues sleeping, feel sluggish, or have other changes. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_8ee0cdf58fcf4c78af43cc94d2d2a201~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  alt="Woman sitting by a window on a winter day"></figure><p>This is a common problem that is caused by a number of factors including: </p><ul>
  <li><strong>Changes to your circadian rhythm</strong> - there is a reduced number of daylight hours during the winter which can disrupt your body's internal clock. </li>
  <li><strong>Serotonin levels</strong> - reduced sunlight can cause a drop in <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/mental-health/serotonin#functions" target="_blank" ><u>serotonin</u></a> (a mood stabilizer). </li>
  <li><strong>Melatonin levels</strong> - changes in the seasons can disrupt your melatonin levels which play a role in your sleep patterns and mood. </li>
</ul><p>(If you experience severe symptoms, you might be experiencing <a href="https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/seasonal-affective-disorder/symptoms-causes/syc-20364651" target="_blank" ><u>seasonal affective disorder</u></a> or "SAD". If your symptoms persist or become severe, you should talk to your doctor or health care professional.) </p>
<h2>Vitamins & Supplements You Should be Taking During the Winter Months</h2>
<p>Feeling crummy for half the year shouldn't be the norm! To help counteract the winter blues, here are some great supplements to take to increase your energy, immunity, and recovery! </p>
<h3>Supplements for Energy</h3>
<p>With less sunshine during the day, your energy can take a hit. Here are Alex's top recommended supplements to boost your energy. These should be taken in the morning for the best effect! </p>
<h4>Ashwagandha</h4>
<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/health/body/ashwagandha-benefits/" target="_blank" ><u>Ashwagandha </u></a>also known as Indian ginseng or winter cherry - is a herb growing in popularity. It's part of the class of plants can adaptogens known for their health benefits when ingested.</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_b1a7fe15e0a04096888c4fa8f1182347~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Ashwagandha is a powerful herb" alt="Ashwagandha root and power on a white background"></figure><p>This non-toxic herb has plenty of benefits - making it a favorite of not on Alex, but other healthcare professionals. Ashwagandha benefits: </p><ul>
  <li>Relieve stress and anxiety</li>
  <li>Lower blood sugar</li>
  <li>Increase muscle strength</li>
  <li>Improve sexual function in women</li>
  <li>Boost testosterone in men</li>
  <li>Sharpen focus </li>
  <li>Support heart health</li>
</ul><p><strong>How to supplement with Ashwagandha: </strong>Alex recommends adding it to your morning coffee or favorite <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/our-top-10-superfoods-list-for-you-freebie" target="_blank" ><u>superfoods smoothie</u></a>. It has a slightly bitter or earthy flavor. </p>
<h4>Maca root</h4>
<p>Originating from Peru, this superfood is supercharged with vitamins, minerals, and has tons of great health benefits. Maca root is perfect for increasing your energy, especially right before a workout because it is full of carbohydrates. Take it after your workout for a quick dose of carbs to help your muscles grow big and recover faster. </p>

<p>Besides increasing your energy, maca may also help <a href="https://www.realsimple.com/food-recipes/recipe-collections-favorites/popular-ingredients/maca-root-benefits" target="_blank" ><u>boost your libido and fertility</u></a>. </p>

<p><strong>How to consume maca root:</strong> add this nutty powder or liquid extract to your smoothies, oatmeal, baked goods, or other favorite dishes. </p>
<h4>caffeine</h4><p>You might be already adding this supplement to your daily diet in the form of your cup of coffee! Caffeine is a great supplement to add to your routine due to its high levels of antioxidants. It also has plenty of <a href="https://www.healthline.com/nutrition/top-13-evidence-based-health-benefits-of-coffee#TOC_TITLE_HDR_5" target="_blank" ><u>health benefits</u></a> like improving your energy levels and improving physical performance. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_a6ec2dd917044b58842596f9efca81ab~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Get the health benefits of caffeine without the jitters" alt="White mug filled with coffee surrounded by loose coffee beans"></figure><p>Want the health benefits of coffee but get the jitters from too much caffeine? Try supplementing with L-theanine, an amino acid that is said to help eliminate the jittery feeling or "take the edge off" when you drink caffeine. </p>

<p>The <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/l-theanine#benefits-and-uses" target="_blank" ><u>benefits of L-theanine</u></a> are: </p><ul>
  <li>Relief of anxiety and stress</li>
  <li>Increased focus </li>
  <li>Better immunity </li>
</ul><p>Plus, if you take this supplement in the evening, it can help initiate sleep so you fall asleep faster and easier! </p>
<h3>Supplements for Immunity</h3>
<p>Protect yourself against the onslaught of germs and viruses this cold and flu season by boosting your natural immunity. Here are the top supplements to strengthen your immune system. </p>
<h4>Vitamin D </h4><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_9b8c38f38a084e5da255391715d62d11~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="With decreased sunshine, supplement with Vitamin D" alt="Hand holding a gel capsule pill up to the sun"></figure><p>Vitamin D is one of those critical vitamins we need that we get from sunlight. With the decreased amount of sunlight every day, it can be beneficial to supplement your diet with vitamin D. </p>

<p>Alex increases her dosage of vitamin D during the winter. You should talk to your doctor about a dosage that is right for you. </p>
<h4>Adaptogens</h4>
<p>What is an <a href="https://www.eatingwell.com/article/292256/what-are-adaptogens-and-are-they-good-for-you/" target="_blank" ><u>adaptogen</u></a>? An adaptogen is a natural substance that is considered to help the body adapt to stress and produce a normalizing effect on bodily processes. Some examples include ginseng and mushrooms such as lion's mane, reishi, and chaga. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_6e8b4c19ba064558a334cb0a881295e1~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Mushroom adaptogens" alt="Lion's mane, reishi, and chaga mushrooms on a plate"></figure><p><strong>How to supplement with adaptogens:</strong> Add adaptogens in their raw forms, as powders, in teas or tinctures, or other supplements.</p>

<p>Alex loves getting powered supplements from <a href="https://www.thegutlab.ca/?utm_campaign_source=Staxcycleclub&#38;utm_campaign_medium=blogpost&#38;utm_campaign_name=Best%20Supplements%20for%20Winter" target="_blank" ><u>The Gut Lab</u></a>. Their <a href="https://www.thegutlab.ca/shop/shroom5?utm_campaign_source=Staxcycleclub&#38;utm_campaign_medium=blogpost&#38;utm_campaign_name=Best%20Supplements%20for%20Winter" target="_blank" ><u>shroom5 </u></a>blend combines chaga, reishi, lion's mane, tremella, and cordyceps mushrooms to support all parts of your body. </p>
<h3>Supplements for Recovery</h3>
<p>Whether you're recovering after an intense workout or from feeling under the weather, here are Alex's top picks for recovery supplements. </p>
<h4>Magnesium</h4>
<p>Magnesium is an important mineral that plays a role in over 300 enzyme reactions in the body. From the regulation of muscle cramps and blood pressure to energy production, blood sugar balancing, weight management, and mood, magnesium plays a critical role. Take note of the type of magnesium you're taking; they are not created equal!</p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_70eee0563db64bc0b97941aea7c92d15~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="You can find magnesium in lots of food sources" alt="different foods such as oats, lentils, beans, spinach, and avocado"></figure><ul>
  <li><strong>Glycinate</strong> - take magnesium glycinate in the morning to help keep everything running smoothly in your bowels and at night to help you sleep. </li>
  <li><strong>Citrate</strong> - this form has a super calming effect and helps with mood regulation, muscle crampings, and aiding in sleep. MagnesiumcCitrate is a great form to take for recovery and at night. </li>
  <li><strong>Malate</strong> - magnesium malate can be taken to increase your intake of magnesium as well as help with muscle soreness. Take in the morning for increased stamina! </li>
  <li><strong>Chloride</strong> - Spritz your skin with magnesium chloride to help with muscle soreness and help ground you. If you're deficient in magnesium (<a href="https://globalnews.ca/news/3957035/signs-of-magnesium-deficiency/#:~:text=Over%20a%20third%20of%20adult,to%20latest%20Statistics%20Canada%20numbers." target="_blank" ><u>as most people are</u></a>) you might experience some tingly when used topically. </li>
</ul><h4>Essential Amino Acids</h4>
<p>In order to maintain good health, the body needs 20 different amino acids. <a href="https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/324229#types" target="_blank" ><u>Essential amino acids</u></a> (EAA) include nine amino acids that we need to get through food. Our bodies don't produce these amino acids naturally, hence the name "essential amino acids". </p>

<p>Supplementing with an essential amino acid product before, during, or after your workout can help with protein synthesis, muscle recovery, and muscle building. </p>

<p><strong>How to supplement EAAs</strong>: If you have a heavy lift day, take EAAs after; if you are doing cardio (like your favorite spin class), sip EAAs during your workout. </p>
<h4>Creatine</h4>
<p>You may have heard about creatine before. It's been a controversial supplement within the fitness world and there is lots of misconception about this supplement. Creatine is a natural substance that turns into creatine phosphate which in turn helps create adenosine triphosphate (ATP). Think of ATP as potential energy in your muscles and creation helps replenish it. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_7ef5f3b2da974361a17a3985a592716c~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Take creatine for recovery" alt="Woman with a shaker cup and a black jug beside her"></figure><p>Creatine can help support lean muscle mass, brain function, and help defend against some neurological disorders. </p>

<p><strong>When to supplement with creatine: </strong>Supplement with creatine before your lift or spin class to help increase stamina and performance. </p>
<h2>What About Fat Burners? </h2>
<p>While definitely not an essential supplement, fat burners come up in the discussion of supplements. Alex reiterates that fat burners are not a magic potion or a silver bullet for weight loss. But for some people whose nutrition and workout regime is on point, you might see some added benefits. </p>

<p>If you are going to supplement with a fat burner, Alex recommends taking L-carnitine 20 to 40 minutes before exercising. </p>
<h2>Supplements to Cure a Hangover</h2>
<p>With the holiday season in full swing, you might find yourself nursing a couple of hangovers. These aren't guaranteed cure-alls, but Alex has a couple of supplement suggestions for helping you feel better after a night out. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_f012370ca5e94ce2bd0431013a6a7867~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Recover from a hangover with these cures" alt="Woman laying on the counter hungover with party decor surrounding her"></figure><ol>
  <li><strong>N-acetyl cysteine (NAC)</strong> - helps produce antioxidants in the body which can reduce toxicity, increase liver function, and counteract drowsiness and nausea. You can try 600 mg before and after drinking to ward off hangovers. </li>
  <li><strong>Alpha-lipoic acid (ALA)</strong> - works the same way as NAC. Try taking 400 mg before your Christmas party. </li>
  <li><strong>Activated charcoal </strong>- pop a couple of activated charcoal tablets before you hit the sheets to help counteract the alcohol in your system. </li>
  <li><strong>Carbohydrates</strong> - it literally has the word "hydrate" in it. Carbs help us hold onto water and keep us hydrated. So use this as an excuse to have a little more carbohydrates at your function to keep your body hydrated. </li>
  <li><strong>Vitamin Bs</strong> - choose a supplement that contains B-1, B-6, and B-12 to help replace the B vitamins lost. </li>
</ol><h2>Tips for Staying on Top of Supplements</h2>
<p>In order to feel the benefits of supplements, you have to take them consistently. Here are three ways to build your supplement habit. </p>
<h3>1. set a reminder</h3>
<p>Put your phone to good use and create a reoccurring reminder to take your supplements. </p>
<h3>2. Make it Part of Your Ritual</h3>
<p>Store your supplements somewhere that is part of your daily ritual - like by your morning coffee station or a nightly cuppa tea. </p>
<h3>3. Practice</h3>
<p>Practice taking them every day. Like every habit, it takes time to build a routine. </p>
 
<hr><p>Taking supplements is all about balance, research, and creating a ritual. Empower yourself with knowledge about different supplements and do what's best for you. Remember that a handful of supplements won't cure all your ailments; you need good nutrition, good sleep, and exercise as a foundation. </p>

<p>What is your must-have daily supplement? </p>

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[3 Adjustments You Need Adopt to Change Your Life]]></title><description><![CDATA[Is your mindset holding you back from reaching your goals? It might be! Lucky for you, we have some tough love for ya! Here are 3...]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/3-adjustments-you-need-adopt-to-change-your-life</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61550279e22d4f00160c68d9</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[mindset]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy habits]]></category><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 16:40:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_302911af7ed44f0f9601651a64a95dc6~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Is your mindset holding you back from reaching your goals? It might be! Lucky for you, we have some tough love for ya! Here are 3 adjustments you need to adopt to change your life. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_302911af7ed44f0f9601651a64a95dc6~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Ready to achieve your goals? Time for your attitude adjustment!" alt="Woman on a spin bike beckoning someone forward"></figure><p>In order to achieve your goals (big or small), your attitude needs to match your aspirations. Yet in some cases, our excuses for why we shouldn't try is our biggest limiting factor. Whether you want to hit a new PR or try a new hobby, the goals you form for yourself begin to take shape as quickly as the reasons why you can't do it.</p>

<p>While self-doubt is totally common - our very own Joelle experienced this before she took on her white whale goal of running 108 kilometers in the BlackSpur race in August - it's our ability to preserve that allows us to accomplish anything! Our mentality is critical in determining whether we will succeed or not. </p>
 <p>Here are three adjustments to make - instead of excuses - to let you live your best life.  </p>
<h2>1. Pivot</h2>
<p>Seriously, even the best-laid plans go awry in life. You need to roll with the punches and be prepared to PIVOT! </p>

<p>When all your plans go to sh*t, it's an opportunity to make an adjustment instead of an excuse of why you can't doing the thing anymore. </p>

<p>Let's do a for instance. You normally hit up your favorite spin class first thing in the morning, but today something else comes up. Your kid doesn't feel well, you woke up late, your dog got into your <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/our-top-10-superfoods-list-for-you-freebie" target="_blank" ><u>superfood</u></a> smoothie... things happen. Instead of throwing up your hands and skipping your workout, what can you do instead? </p>

<p><strong>You can pivot</strong>. Choose a <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/on-demand" target="_blank" ><u>25 Express</u></a> workout, ride in the afternoon or evening, or take an unexpected rest day and workout tomorrow. </p>

<p>Change your direction but not the destination. You can still accomplish your goal (working out) but in a different way. </p> <h2>2. Prioritize</h2>
<p>When you want to achieve something - a half marathon or learning to bake - you have to fit it into your life (and schedule). But finding time to add something new to your list can feel impossible. Well, here's the tough love:</p>

<p>Instead of saying "I don't have time", say "it's not a priority". For everything on your list of things to do, say that. Let that roll around in your mind. How does it make you feel? </p>

<p>When you skip Sunday morning spin class because you got carried away binge-watching Netflix, what you're really saying is "my health isn't a priority". </p>

<p>Instead of making up reasons why you can't, look at the things that truly aren't a priority. These are things that really don't serve you anymore. Toxic friendships, binge eating, burning yourself out. Let them go and prioritize what matters. </p>

<p><strong>New mantra: I am a priority.</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_320dcbd9859e42b5b466db5bb5966075~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Repeat after me, "I am a priority"" alt="Caucasian woman with a ponytail with her hands in prayer"></figure><h2>3. Start</h2>
<p>"<strong>A journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step</strong>"</p>

<p>Just start. If you get the ball rolling, you can harness the power of the <a href="https://www.wideawakebusiness.com/blog/momentum-mindset/" target="_blank" ><u>Momentum Mindset</u></a>. The Momentum Mindset is the belief that once you start, you will continue moving forward despite obstacles and missteps. Instead of running into stop signs, you proceed with direction signs. </p>

<p>That's not all. People who make the adjustment from an excuse to the Momentum Mindset, succeed because they practice the following: </p><ul>
  <li>Reject limiting beliefs</li>
  <li>Anticipate challenges and plan how to overcome them</li>
  <li>Get back up quickly after a fall</li>
  <li>Adjust their direction, not their destination</li>
</ul><a href="https://youtu.be/VSceuiPBpxY">https://youtu.be/VSceuiPBpxY</a>
<hr><p>Life is too short to let excuses hold you back. Instead of letting your own mind be your limiting factor, dream big and make these three adjustments - you will change your life! </p>

<p>What is the biggest mindset adjustment you've made that has positively impacted your life? </p>

<p>Share these adjustments with a friend who needs to change their mindset! </p> 

]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[6 Genius TikTok Fitness Hacks You Wish You’d Known About Sooner!]]></title><description><![CDATA[6 Genius TikTok Fitness Hacks You Wish You'd Known About Sooner! We scoured TikTok for the best fitness hacks so you wouldn’t have to. ]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/6-genius-tiktok-fitness-hacks-you-wish-you-d-known-about-sooner</link><guid isPermaLink="false">615f62a09efb0100166fc1b7</guid><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[nutrition]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy eating]]></category><category><![CDATA[fitness hacks]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 17:23:58 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/85bcec_aa5c46cfd3984bcb885a70295a3660f9~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_900,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s hard to remember a time before TikTok graced the world with hacks that are so easy to find and share. It’s an incredible thing what the hive mind can come up with to make things in our daily lives easier! Nowadays, you can find a TikTok hack for nearly anything: cleaning, studying, organizing, fashion, beauty, and the list goes on. You name it, there’s a hack for that! </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_6be2f92c482b4eaa9864cd3124f21ff9~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="We're here to make the fitness grind a little easier" alt="Woman sitting on pavement tying her running shoes"></figure><p>Hey, if it’s going to make my life easier, sign me up! We scoured TikTok for the best fitness hacks so you wouldn’t have to. Whether you need a little extra motivation this morning or you’re looking for ideas on how to keep your hair fresh during and after a workout, check out these gym hacks we found just for you!</p>
<h2><strong>6 Brilliant Fitness Hacks for STAX </strong></h2>
<h2><strong>(best viewed from a computer!)</strong></h2><h3><strong>A Motivational Kick in the Butt</strong></h3>
<p>Let’s start here because, let’s be real for a second, sometimes the hardest part of a workout is just getting there! We could all use a little extra motivation sometimes, so if you’re feeling a little sore or tired or lazy this morning, check out this hack.</p>

<p>TikTok user <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@austindilbert" target="_blank" ><u>@austindilbert</u></a> teams up with our boy MJ to pump some motivation and energy into your body! If you’re feeling sluggish, all you need to do is watch this video a few times and feel the 80s aerobic energy. Austin has enough energy to go around!</p>

<p>Clip not loading from your phone? <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@austindilbert/video/6974117726713302278?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.staxcycleclub.com%2F&#38;referer_video_id=6974117726713302278&#38;refer=embed" target="_blank" ><u>Click here</u></a> to view!</p> <h3><strong>Standing Up To The Man</strong></h3>
<p>We’ve all been there. You’re just trying to get a workout in but you can feel someone’s eye burning a hole in the side of your face. What gives?</p>

<p>This straightforward hack is meant to flip the switch. TikTok user <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@marissacpt" target="_blank" ><u>@marissacpt</u></a> lays it out for us plain and simple. If someone is staring at you and making you uncomfortable, just stare back and hit ‘em with that flex!</p>

<p>The gym is a place meant where people can go to better themselves and their health. You have just as much right to be there as anyone else. You’re part of the STAX fam, so use this hack to show everyone that you won’t make yourself small for anyone!</p>


<p>Clip not loading from your phone? <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@marissacpt/video/6887627278679903493?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.staxcycleclub.com%2F&#38;referer_video_id=6887627278679903493&#38;refer=embed" target="_blank" ><u>Click here</u></a> to view!</p> <h3><strong>Pretty Cup Love, You’re the One I Lean On</strong></h3>
<p>Sometimes a fitness hack is so dang simple it just makes sense! We know it’s a struggle to get the recommended amount of water in a day, with suggestions ranging from 64 oz to 2.7 liters and everything in between. So how can we guarantee that we’re getting enough water?</p>

<p>According to TikTok user <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@vpopitdontstop" target="_blank" ><u>@vpopitdontstop</u></a>, you need to get yourself a pretty cup! With a fancy cup that makes you feel like a bad b*tch, you’ll be more inclined to be sipping on water all day long and make sure that your body is well hydrated.</p>

<p>Getting enough H20 on a daily basis is so important. </p><ul>
  <li>It keeps your joints lubricated</li>
  <li>Helps you sleep better</li>
  <li>Keeps your brain functioning properly</li>
  <li>Improves your mood</li>
  <li>Regulates body temperature</li>
</ul><p>Snag yourself a<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Kate-Spade-New-York-Insulated/dp/B07MCYV81F/ref=asc_df_B07MCYV81F/?tag=hyprod-20&#38;linkCode=df0&#38;hvadid=309727307406&#38;hvpos=&#38;hvnetw=g&#38;hvrand=5324574410508578259&#38;hvpone=&#38;hvptwo=&#38;hvqmt=&#38;hvdev=c&#38;hvdvcmdl=&#38;hvlocint=&#38;hvlocphy=9027605&#38;hvtargid=pla-635489126369&#38;psc=1" target="_blank" > ,<u>fun</u></a>,<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Reusable-Twerking-Perfect-Frosted-Smoothies/dp/B0958TFW9T/ref=sr_1_19?dchild=1&#38;keywords=funny+cup+with+straw&#38;qid=1633627674&#38;s=home-garden&#38;sr=1-19" target="_blank" > ,<u>badass</u></a>,<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Insulated-Reusable-Silicone-Motivational-Drinking/dp/B082877RRB/ref=sr_1_4?dchild=1&#38;keywords=motivational+cup+with+straw&#38;qid=1633627617&#38;s=home-garden&#38;sr=1-4" target="_blank" > ,<u>helpful</u></a>, or<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Color-Changing-Tumbler-Cups-Straws/dp/B092SPLVS8/ref=sr_1_28?dchild=1&#38;keywords=funny+cup+with+straw&#38;qid=1633627720&#38;s=home-garden&#38;sr=1-28" target="_blank" > ,<u>funky</u></a> cup and keep that agua flowing!</p>


<p>Clip not loading from your phone? <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@vpopitdontstop/video/6894355690219949318?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.staxcycleclub.com%2F&#38;referer_video_id=6894355690219949318&#38;refer=embed" target="_blank" ><u>Click here </u></a>to view!</p> <h3><strong>We Like It Thick</strong></h3>
<p>Make it thick and sticky like your favorite mountain climber track!</p>

<p>Not all smoothies are created equal. Some smoothies just reign supreme. But how can we take our smoothies to the next level? TikTok user <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@kizedwards_?lang=en" target="_blank" ><u>@kizedwards_</u></a> has let the secret out of the bag! The key is frozen bananas! </p>

<p>For this fitness hack, all you have to do is chop up your bananas when they’re ripe, throw them in a plastic bag or container, and pop them in the freezer. It’s that easy! Not only do frozen bananas give your smoothies the perfect, creamy consistency, but you can also use them for <em>nicecream</em> (a healthy, vegan alternative to ice cream) or smoothie bowls!</p>

<p>For the perfect healthy breakfast, throw your frozen nanners into the blender with some of our <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/our-top-10-superfoods-list-for-you-freebie" target="_blank" >,<u>favorite superfoods</u></a>! We love a blend of banana and acai topped with cacao nibs, chia, and hemp seeds. *Chef’s Kiss*</p>

<p>Clip not loading from your phone? <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@kizedwards_/video/7015718966182153474?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.staxcycleclub.com%2F&#38;referer_video_id=7015718966182153474&#38;refer=embed" target="_blank" ><u>Click here </u></a>to view!</p> <h3><strong>Keeping That Mane Under Control</strong></h3>
<p>Have you ever talked yourself out of a workout just because you don’t want to wash your hair? No? Just us? Well, that excuse is going out the window with this gym hack on how to handle your sweaty hair during intense workouts.</p>

<p>Low ponytails, dry shampoo, and a blow dryer are the key here! <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@gabiburgfit" target="_blank" ><u>@gabiburgfit</u></a> breaks it down for us. She says that dry shampoo will be your best friend throughout the week. Using dry shampoo both before and after your workout will help you soak up all the sweat. We love classic <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Batiste-Shampoo-Original-Citrus-Quantity/dp/B008CYGSZC/ref=asc_df_B008CYGSZC/?tag=hyprod-20&#38;linkCode=df0&#38;hvadid=459692508362&#38;hvpos=&#38;hvnetw=g&#38;hvrand=16620164690193659674&#38;hvpone=&#38;hvptwo=&#38;hvqmt=&#38;hvdev=c&#38;hvdvcmdl=&#38;hvlocint=&#38;hvlocphy=9027605&#38;hvtargid=pla-943193094442&#38;psc=1" target="_blank" ><u>Batiste</u></a> or Moroccan Oil which comes in options for both <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Moroccanoil-Dark-Tones-Shampoo-Ounce/dp/B00VVS9O6G/ref=asc_df_B00VVS9O6G/?tag=hyprod-20&#38;linkCode=df0&#38;hvadid=309750549832&#38;hvpos=&#38;hvnetw=g&#38;hvrand=2337577155093210875&#38;hvpone=&#38;hvptwo=&#38;hvqmt=&#38;hvdev=c&#38;hvdvcmdl=&#38;hvlocint=&#38;hvlocphy=9027605&#38;hvtargid=pla-407336936065&#38;psc=1" target="_blank" ><u>dark</u></a> and <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Moroccanoil-Dry-Shampoo-Light-Tones/dp/B00VXO5RPK/ref=asc_df_B00VXO5RPK/?tag=hyprod-20&#38;linkCode=df0&#38;hvadid=312049381675&#38;hvpos=&#38;hvnetw=g&#38;hvrand=2337577155093210875&#38;hvpone=&#38;hvptwo=&#38;hvqmt=&#38;hvdev=c&#38;hvdvcmdl=&#38;hvlocint=&#38;hvlocphy=9027605&#38;hvtargid=pla-437735172932&#38;psc=1" target="_blank" ><u>light</u></a> tones.</p>

<p>Clip not loading from your phone? <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@gabiburgfit/video/6987790903138094342?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.staxcycleclub.com%2F&#38;referer_video_id=6987790903138094342&#38;refer=embed" target="_blank" ><u>Click here </u></a>to view!</p> <h3><strong>One for the Kiddos</strong></h3>
<p>We know what it can be like as a <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/combining-fitness-and-pregnancy" target="_blank" ><u>parent</u></a>. Your kids want to do everything that their parents do! Do your kids ever try to ask if they can join you when you hop on your bike and hit one of our <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/on-demand" target="_blank" ><u>virtual spin classes</u></a>? Well with this at-home workout hack, now they can.</p>

<p>Tiktok user <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@crazysiblings" target="_blank" ><u>@crazysiblings</u></a> shows us how simple it is to turn a regular kid’s bike with training wheels into a stationary bike for tiny humans! All you have to do is prop up their training wheels on a few books, and they’re good to go.</p>

<p>Let us be the first to warn you though, kids have energizer bunny energy! There’s a good chance they’ll barely crack a sweat and have you wondering why you’re exhausted and they’re ready for round two.</p>

<p>Clip not loading from your phone? <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@crazysiblings/video/6931931089745235205?referer_url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.staxcycleclub.com%2F&#38;referer_video_id=6931931089745235205&#38;refer=embed&#38;is_copy_url=1&#38;is_from_webapp=v1" target="_blank" ><u>Click here </u></a>to view!</p> <p>It never ceases to amaze us how innovative people can be. With the power of social media, people can share their brilliant ideas which can really enrich all of our lives. The fitness hacks go on for miles over on TikTok, and there is always something new popping up!</p>

<p>What’s the best fitness hack that you’ve seen lately? Spread the love in the comments!</p>
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mental Toughness is a Marathon Not a Sprint: How to Build Mental Resilience]]></title><description><![CDATA[How to build mental resilience to help you achieve your goals and build healthy habits.]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/mental-toughness-is-a-marathon-not-a-sprint-how-to-build-mental-resilience</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6169db9aa6079600160d58c4</guid><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[mindset]]></category><category><![CDATA[mental health]]></category><category><![CDATA[mental toughness]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 19:14:32 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/85bcec_ca47190b3cdf43bf9219a078c6690e4e~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever witnessed someone doing a seemingly impossible task - like running an ultra-marathon - and thought "how do they do that?" It's simple: mental resilience. But being mentally tough isn't just for those huge insurmountable goals. Building mental resilience is for building healthy habits, maintaining fitness goals, and pushing through when things (like life) get tough. </p>

<p>For most of us, building mental resiliency and toughness is a work-in-progress; it's something that takes years to build and doesn't happen overnight. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_39720731d1854885be0a8c6c9b319a05~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_960,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Photo by @joelle_t" alt="Woman running across bridge over water with downtown Calgary in the background"></figure><h2>What is Mental Resilience</h2>
<p>Mental resilience isn't just your ability to bounce back from tough situations. It's also your capacity to adapt in the face of challenging circumstances - all while maintaining stable mental wellbeing. </p>

<p>These challenging circumstances don't have to be huge, life-changing events. We all face challenges in our everyday lives. Things like getting up at the first alarm, pushing through a tough workout, or staying on track with <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/our-top-10-superfoods-list-for-you-freebie" target="_blank" ><u>healthy eating</u></a> are all examples of events that build our mental toughness. </p>
<h2>Joelle Talks Having Grit to Run a Marathon</h2>
<p>That example of someone doing a seemingly impossible task in the beginning? Yeah, we know her. Stax's very own Joelle (<a href="https://www.instagram.com/joelle_t/" target="_blank" ><u>@joelle_t</u></a>) is a living embodiment of <a href="https://www.learningscientists.org/blog/2018/4/19-1" target="_blank" ><u>grit</u></a>. </p>

<p>In August 2021, Joelle was one of the 500 racers to run the <a href="https://www.sinistersports.ca/blackspur/" target="_blank" ><u>Black Spur Ultra</u></a> - a 108 kilometer run through the mountains. But she didn't just wake up that morning and decide to go for a run. </p>

<p>No, her journey to accomplishing this ultra-goal was <em>years</em> in the making - a whole decade actually!</p> <h3>Pushing Past The Wall</h3>
<p>Before Joelle became the fitness coach and ultra-marathon running champ we know now, she started at the beginning. After a hiatus from sports after high school, Jo got back into running while in university. Like anyone who is just starting out with anything, she didn't just step out as an expert. In fact, she says she was "atrocious" at running and it was "really, really hard". </p>

<p>But she stuck to it. In the beginning, she started out with 5-kilometer runs and just kept going. Then at around 19 years old, she ran her first half marathon (that's around 21 kilometers). That <a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/runners-high" target="_blank" ><u>runner's high</u></a> got her hooked! </p><p>Summarized into two neat paragraphs, you might think that building up from a 5 km run to over 100 km just happens like that. But it doesn't. As Jo explains, her progress didn't happen immediately. Her first half marathon was when she was 19 and her first ultra-marathon was at 30 - that's over 10 years! </p>

<p>In that decade of time, Jo didn't just train her body to run further and further. She trained her mind. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_e1c49deabb764fcb875c8c56c65a175f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_720,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Photo by @joelle_t" alt="Woman in blue jacket running on a trail in the woods"></figure><h3>Building a Grit Mindset</h3>
<p>There's no shortcut to building your own grit mindset. To be like Jo and accomplish your goals, it all comes down to putting your head down and do the work needed. "Your body will do what your mind is telling it to do," says Joelle. </p>

<p>On tough days, your mind might put up a mental block. Jo explains that when this happens - as it will - you have to recognize the hurt and push through. Now pushing through doesn't mean ignoring injuries. That's a different pain. </p>

<p>But when you're tired or hungry or have blisters, keep going forward. In fact, a mantra that helped her through the toughest of periods was this simply: <em>forward is a pace</em>.</p>
<h2>How to Build Mental Resilience</h2>
<p>Joelle isn't the only person to have discovered the power of having grit. Neuroscientists, psychologists, athletes, and more have been studying mental toughness - and learning how to build it. Here are 5 ways to build your own mental resilience. </p>
<h3>1. Well-laid plans</h3>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_7f6f2e872beb408f8e396a07f0fae99c~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  alt="Colorful post-it notes on a board"></figure><p>Big goals can seem really, really scary until you remember that all these goals came out from very well-laid-out plans. </p>

<p>Instead of becoming overwhelmed with the hugeness of your goal - break your big goal into smaller, more attainable pieces. Write the steps down so you can see how easy to manage each bite-size piece is. </p>

<p>For Jo, her goal of running a 108 km race had to fit into her busy life, which includes waking up at 3 A.M. every day for work. So her plan needed to be personalized yet precise. The ultra-marathon was broken into 16 weeks and was displayed on a huge calendar on her wall where she could check off mini-accomplishments.</p>
<h3>2. Accountability</h3><blockquote>"When you look yourself in the mirror, that's the one person you can't lie to." - <a href="https://www.gwenelliot.ca/blogs/news/david-goggins-5-challenges-to-build-mental-toughness" target="_blank" ><u>David Goggins</u></a>, toughest man alive</blockquote>
<p>Accountability starts with you. <strong>Try this:</strong> on your bathroom or vanity mirror, put post-it notes with your goals so you can see them every day. </p>

<p>Need some accountability support? Get your friends involved with your goals. Joelle loves to drag all her spin friends onto the trails for a run. Having friends act as accountability partners helps keep you on the right path. </p>
<h3>3. Visualization</h3>
<p><a href="https://esportshealthcare.com/power-of-visualization/" target="_blank" ><u>Visualization is a powerful tool</u></a> to help you reach your goals and live out your dreams. Not only does it help your mind prepare and teach itself how to respond to a situation before it happens (like when you accomplish your big goal), but it also conditions your brain to see, hear, and feel the success in your mind. </p>

<p>Visualize the finish, the ball in the net, crossing the finish line. Visualize how good you will feel when you finish what you started. </p>
<h3>4. Delayed Gratification</h3>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_89f560bf43744946ab002ebc9c1d8ec6~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_699,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Incredible photo capturing a woman's happiness after completing the Boston Marathon. Photo by Ben Gavin." alt="A woman celebrating at the end of a maraton"></figure><p>As people, it's an inborn principle that humans are wired to seek instant gratification. But by <a href="https://www.tonyrobbins.com/achieve-lasting-weight-loss/delayed-gratification/" target="_blank" ><u>delaying gratification</u></a> - that is, resisting the temptation of an immediate reward and waiting for a better award - we can build mental toughness and help with impulse control. </p>

<p><strong>Check out more of these amazing photos: </strong><a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/piapeterson/boston-marathon-finish-race-photos" target="_blank" ><u>Incredible Photos Of Boston Marathoners’ Joy And Pain As They Cross The Finish Line</u></a> </p>
<h3>5. Mantras</h3>
<p>Lastly, when times are tough and you're in the midst of that marathon session that feels like it will never end, utilize success mantras. Success mantras are affirmations that you make to yourself that can help change your thinking. Here are some success mantras to try: </p><ul>
  <li>Forward is a pace.</li>
  <li>I am destined for big success in life.</li>
  <li>My business/website/career is growing, expanding, and thriving.</li>
  <li>I wake up happy and excited every single day.</li>
  <li>I am a powerful creator. I create the life I want and enjoy it.</li>
</ul><hr><p>Now in the words of Britney Spears, "You better work, bitch!"</p>

<p>What is the huge goal that you're working towards? Share it below with us!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Our Favorite Resistance Bands + How To Use Them!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Here are our favorite resistance bands for breaking a sweat + building sexy muscle! Plus, we share some tips for how to use them. ]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/our-favorite-resistance-bands-how-to-use-them</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61427c0607d7c700164068d0</guid><category><![CDATA[fitness equipment]]></category><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><category><![CDATA[strength training]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 19:01:40 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_25e57b20d061426c9c169d6f972d9958~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you've been online at all lately, you've probably seen the hype of resistance bands! Maybe you're in the market for a set, or are looking for a way to up the ante of your current workout regime. Here are our favorite resistance bands for breaking a sweat! Plus, we share some tips for how to use them. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_732e32cc898b4cd5abb5659a20fdcc16~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Time to ditch the dumbbells for resistance bands!" alt="Stack of dumbbells in a spin studio."></figure><p>Similar to a giant elastic band, resistance bands are usually made from latex or rubber. You can loop them around your legs, arms, or a stationary object in order to increase the tension when you work out. </p>

<p>We love incorporating resistance (spring shift to the right!) and resistance bands turn up the burn in our <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/" target="_blank" ><u>stackables classes</u></a>!</p>

<p><strong>Read more: </strong><a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/5-best-spin-bikes-for-home" target="_blank" ><strong><u>5 Best Sping Bikes for Home</u></strong></a><strong> </strong></p>
<h2>3 Benefits of Resistance Bands</h2>
<p>Let's dive into the benefits of exercise bands. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_ed07c93f4fea4f849ec57d54d3fb76e1~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  alt="Woman using resistance bands to workout"></figure><h3>1. Great for beginners</h3>
<p>Don't let the weight room intimidate you. Resistance loops add just the right about of resistance when you're learning the fundamentals. </p>
<h3>2. Build Lean Muscles</h3>
<p>Tone up that healthy bod! A set of good resistance bands can help you build lean muscle when you go through the movement slowly and with intention. </p>

<p>Unlike free weights, exercise bands keep your muscles under tension for longer and through the entire range of motion. Not only is the muscle working during the concentric part of the movement, but it also works during the eccentric part as well. </p>
<h3>3. Stay fit when traveling</h3>
<p>We promise things are going to get back to normal. And when they do, tossing a set of gym bands into your suitcase is a great way to break a sweat when you're exploring the world. </p>
<blockquote><strong>I love incorporating resistance bands into my workouts because they can be used for a variety of training purposes. </strong></blockquote>
<blockquote><strong>- Janelle from @lifewithpandj</strong></blockquote><h2>The Best Resistance Bands That We Love</h2>
<p>Now that you've read the pros, here are the top resistance bands that we love!</p>
<h3><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Renoj-Booty-Exercise-Resistance-Levels%E3%80%91/dp/B087R2Q4HM/ref=sr_1_3_sspa?crid=2JW5VZKI3SEP9&#38;dchild=1&#38;keywords=resistance+bands&#38;qid=1631748196&#38;sr=8-3-spons&#38;psc=1&#38;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUFGUkJXU01JRzNQVk0mZW5jcnlwdGVkSWQ9QTAwNTg4ODBDQ04yUEJXTFpQMUUmZW5jcnlwdGVkQWRJZD1BMDg3NzU1MzFJVzNaODFCRlBQU1gmd2lkZ2V0TmFtZT1zcF9hdGYmYWN0aW9uPWNsaWNrUmVkaXJlY3QmZG9Ob3RMb2dDbGljaz10cnVl" target="_blank" ><u>Glute Bands</u></a> - a.k.a. The Hip Circle</h3>
<p>The hip circle has taken the fitness industry by storm. Originally introduced by <a href="https://markbellslingshot.com/products/hip-circle" target="_blank" ><u>Mark Bell</u></a>, the glute band is a staple for everyone serious about growing a booty!</p>

<p>This booty band set is non-slip, meaning it won't roll down when you're in the middle of your set. It's also durable, so it won't lose its tension after time. Lastly, this pack of 3 comes with 3 different levels of resistance so you can keep challenging yourself. </p>
<h3>Best <a href="https://www.amazon.com/UPOWEX-Resistance-Whatafit-Exercise-Training/dp/B07DWSPQQY/ref=sr_1_1_sspa?dchild=1&#38;keywords=resistance+bands+set&#38;qid=1631807628&#38;sr=8-1-spons&#38;psc=1&#38;spLa=ZW5jcnlwdGVkUXVhbGlmaWVyPUEzOFFIT1A3SUhXTTRBJmVuY3J5cHRlZElkPUEwOTgyODAwV0ZOWlM0U1kxR0lRJmVuY3J5cHRlZEFkSWQ9QTAzMTQ0NzUzMjg5UFNPODNaNzNNJndpZGdldE5hbWU9c3BfYXRmJmFjdGlvbj1jbGlja1JlZGlyZWN0JmRvTm90TG9nQ2xpY2s9dHJ1ZQ==" target="_blank" ><u>Resistance Band Set</u></a> </h3>
<p>Looking for a complete weight room or home gym option? This resistance band set is perfect for stepping up your game. </p>

<p>This set comes with 2 handles, 2 ankle attachments, a door anchor, and a convenient carry bag. Plus, there are 5 bands with varying weight resistances - from 10 lbs all the way up to 50 lbs! These workout bands are perfect for challenging yourself in our Stax sculpt classes.</p>

<p>Want even more? Personal trainer Petra Mace shared her top fav resistance band brands! </p><ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/Bands-Extra-Thick-Exercise-Resistance/dp/B077GJT2WT" target="_blank" ><u>The X Bands</u></a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.popflexactive.com/collections/booty-bands" target="_blank" ><u>Popflex</u></a></li>
  <li><a href="https://peachbands.com/" target="_blank" ><u>Peachbands</u></a> </li>
</ul> 
 <h2>Tips for Making the Most of Your Resistance Bands</h2>
<p>We're not going to lie, strength bands are not the same as free weights. Here are some tips for making the most of your workout when you utilize your favorite set of resistance bands. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_ef2bbd7f509f41beb8f9c9e3cbce022d~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  alt="Man using resistance bands to exercise"></figure><h3>Body awareness + Intention</h3>
<p>The top tip for strengthening your muscles and getting the best workout with resistance bands is body awareness and intention. </p>

<p>Create a mind-muscle connection for every rep and exercise. Because the weight might be less than what you can get with free weights, you need to go through the rep slowly and with intention. Don't just go through the movement. </p>

<p>Janelle from<strong> </strong><a href="https://www.instagram.com/lifewithpandj/" target="_blank" ><u>@lifewithpandj</u></a> shares her resistance band workout advice:</p>
<blockquote><strong>Biggest tip: the adduction (coming towards the center of the body) is just as important as the abduction (pulling away from the center of the body). Think of this as the "lift and lower" of resistance band work. The focus should be on the control of the entire movement, being in control of actively engaging the muscles at work and remaining in control as you release the tension. </strong></blockquote><h3>Good Form</h3>
<p>Just like with free weights, good form is crucial for using resistance bands. If you can't control the resistance - your legs or arms feel like they're going to snap back to the starting position - then the resistance is too high. Performing the move with bad form is counterintuitive to any strength gains. </p>
<h3>Progressive Overload</h3>
<p>You might have heard the term "progressive overload" but might not know what it means. </p><blockquote><a href="https://www.healthline.com/health/progressive-overload" target="_blank" ><u>Progressive overload</u></a> is when you gradually increase the weight, frequency, or number of repetitions in your strength training routine.</blockquote><p>How does this apply to your resistance band workout? The same way it applies to dumbbells. Start with the lighter resistance and work your way up. Plow through your plateaus by challenging yourself and changing up your workouts. </p>

<p>This principle of progressive overload also applies to your cardiovascular workouts! As you get stronger, you can turn up the dial in your favorite <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/virtual-studio" target="_blank" ><u>Stax spin class</u></a> and get stronger! </p>

<p>Are you ready to up the intensity in your workout? Try incorporating resistance bands into your workouts and watch those muscles pop! Here's a quick upper body sequence you can try today (repeat 3x for the ultimate burn!)</p>
<a href="https://video.wixstatic.com/video/85bcec_9b78f20d5c57416298274dedf138dea0/480p/mp4/file.mp4">https://video.wixstatic.com/video/85bcec_9b78f20d5c57416298274dedf138dea0/480p/mp4/file.mp4</a><p>Ready to up the intensity? We're waiting for you - #LETSMISBEHAVE</p>
 ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Our Top 10 Superfoods List For You! (+ Freebie!)]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hey, Stax fam! We have compiled a list of our favorite, top 10 superfoods for you to try. Plus, score your very own copy of the top 100...]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/our-top-10-superfoods-list-for-you-freebie</link><guid isPermaLink="false">611e946d9b02b900150d1895</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[nutrition]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy eating]]></category><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 15:36:35 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_5ba367562c7442bd989ca3834d5c863b~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey, Stax fam! We have compiled a list of our favorite, top 10 superfoods for you to try. Plus, score your very own copy of the top 100 superfoods.</p>
<h2>What is a Superfood? </h2>
<p>You might have the word "superfoods" thrown around without knowing exactly what it means. This isn't just a gimmick word. Superfoods are a particular food or ingredient that is considered ultra nutritious or nutrient-dense - aka "super"!</p>

<p>Superfoods can be particularly high in vitamins, minerals, antioxidants, or other properties that support overall health and wellbeing. </p>
<h2>Our Favorite, Top 10 Superfoods</h2><h3>1. Acai</h3>
<p>First up is the super popular acai (ah-sigh-EE) berry. Does this superfood live up to all it's hype? </p>
<p>While super delicious as the base of a smoothie bowl, acai berries (like all berries) have a host of nutritional benefits. They contain the antioxidant <a href="https://www.medicalnewstoday.com/articles/305576#nutrition" target="_blank" ><u>anthocyanin</u></a> which is great for:</p><ul>
  <li>Cognitive function</li>
  <li>Heart health</li>
  <li>Possible cancer prevention</li>
</ul><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_efff213c5bec407881f04b9c383dddf1~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  alt="Acai berry smoothie bowl surrounded by superfoods"></figure>
<h3>2. Raw hemp seeds</h3>
<p>Hemp seeds (or hemp hearts) are an incredible source of plant-based protein, healthy fats, and <a href="https://www.webmd.com/diet/hemp-seeds-good-for-you#1" target="_blank" ><u>various vitamins and minerals</u></a> like: </p><ul>
  <li>Iron</li>
  <li>Vitamin E</li>
  <li>Manganese</li>
  <li>Magnesium</li>
  <li>B-vitamins </li>
  <li>Zinc</li>
  <li>Omega-3 and omega-6 essential fatty acids</li>
</ul><p>Eat them raw, roasted, hemp hearts, hemp oil, or mix your favorite smoothie with a hemp powder protein.</p>
<h3>3. kale</h3>
<p>If you don't like kale, I feel bad for you son, 'cause I got 99 problems but super greens ain't one! </p>

<p>Kale is one of the most nutritious vegetables available. It’s a great source of various vitamins and minerals and contains fiber for healthy digestion and elimination. Consume kale raw (make sure to massage it!), as "kale chips", or sauteed.</p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_506869283f6f413ca8fdce2e51778f5f~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  alt="Dark green dinosaur kale leaves"></figure><h3>4. Lemon</h3>
<p>Next up on our list are lemons. These tart yellow fruits are boasting with vitamin C, a potent antioxidant. Squeeze some lemon into your water to reap the benefits of increased metabolism, digestion support, and stimulating your liver.  </p>
<h3>5. Pumpkin</h3>
<p>We aren't talking about pumpkin spice lattes. </p>

<p>Pumpkins are high in fiber which makes it good for you. But it is also rich in beta-carotene which may help protect against developing type 2 diabetes. Did you know that <a href="https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&#38;rct=j&#38;q=&#38;esrc=s&#38;source=web&#38;cd=&#38;cad=rja&#38;uact=8&#38;ved=2ahUKEwjZj7X11b3yAhW6JjQIHe_SBhUQFnoECAwQAw&#38;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.cdc.gov%2Fdiabetes%2Fbasics%2Fquick-facts.html&#38;usg=AOvVaw1Mr2_pItQPO_85DvX1C_0O" target="_blank" ><u>type 2 diabetes accounts for approximately 90% - 95% of all diagnosed cases of diabetes</u></a>?</p>

<p>Compounds in this fruit can improve insulin resistance and improve glucose tolerance.</p>
<h3>6. beets</h3>
<p>That beautiful berry color of beetroot comes from betalains, a type of natural plant pigment that provides a health boost. Not only do beets feed your body with betalains, but they also contain fiber, nitrates, and vitamins and minerals. </p>

<p>Nitrates help widen your blood vessels - so beets may <a href="https://health.clevelandclinic.org/the-health-benefits-of-beets/" target="_blank" >,<u>help improve your athletic performance</u></a>. </p>

<p>Like when you're rocking out to the beet in the <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/virtual-studio" target="_blank" >,<u>Stax </u><u>virtual</u>,<u> studio</u></a>. ;) </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_29e1b224db1f4f569c469a862fc28d03~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  alt="beetroots"></figure><h3>7. Chia Seeds</h3>
<p>These gooey little seeds are filled with fiber and healthy fats. Chia seeds make a great addition to your diet because they can help curb cravings, balance blood sugar, and support healthy digestion. </p>
<h3>8. Dandelion</h3>
<p>Not just a nuisance to your lawn, but dandelion weeds are a super green. The green portion of the plant is supportive for liver health, weight loss, and acts as a diuretic. </p><p>From roots to flowers, dandelions are a source of vitamins A, C, and K. They also provide substantial amounts of iron, calcium, magnesium, and potassium. </p>

<p>This superfood also contains inulin which is a soluble fiber that supports the growth and maintenance of <a href="https://www.healthline.com/nutrition/dandelion-benefits#TOC_TITLE_HDR_2" target="_blank" ><u>healthy bacteria flora in your gut</u></a>. </p>
<h3>9. Cacao (aka dark chocolate)</h3>
<p>As if we need a reason to eat chocolate! </p>

<p>Dark chocolate (containing 70% or more cacao) can be a delicious superfood. <a href="https://www.webmd.com/diet/health-benefits-cacao-powder#1" target="_blank" ><u>Cacao</u></a> has been shown to help lower blood pressure, reduce your risk of diabetes, and contribute to a healthy heart. Plus, cacao powder is also an excellent source of iron, protein, magnesium, potassium, and fiber.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_8d2bf7577d5a451d8b19afbc866540b0~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_800,al_c,q_80/file.png"  alt="cacao nibs in a measuring cup"></figure><h3>10. Ghee</h3>
<p>Last up, is ghee. Ghee is clarified butter which is butter that has been boiled down until only the fats are left. </p>

<p>While ghee is high in saturated fats, it also contains medium-chain triglycerides (MCTs). MCTs have been shown to help contribute to reducing body weight. Another compound, butyrate, has been shown to balance insulin levels and aid in digestive health. </p>

<p>Look for ghee from organic, grass-fed cows for optimal nutritional value.</p>
<hr><p>These are just our top 10 superfoods. In reality, there are 100s of amazing, nutritionally jam-packed foods out there. </p>

<p>We've put together a list of the top 100 superfoods in our newly launched Members Area! Click the link below and make sure you're logged in to explore!</p> 
 <p>What is your favorite superfood?!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Women Are Amazing: Combining Fitness and Pregnancy]]></title><description><![CDATA[As the 2020 Olympics come to a close, we saw an incredible shift for women athletes - particularly athletes who are mothers. It's about...]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/combining-fitness-and-pregnancy</link><guid isPermaLink="false">61157b07abec8b00166f8d29</guid><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><category><![CDATA[pregnancy fitness]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 22:23:14 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_e1c72dc369864f17a7e99551578eaef9~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As the 2020 Olympics come to a close, we saw an incredible shift for women athletes - particularly athletes who are mothers. It's about time but pregnant athletes and new moms are more visible than ever! Our very own Stax instructor (and amazing mom) Alex shares her perspective on pregnancy fitness and staying healthy after pregnancy. </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_22d6beb86145432ba030940fca105174~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Stax spin instructor Alex featuring baby Coco" alt="Pregnant woman on an indoor spin cycling bike"></figure><p>"<a href="https://www.runnersworld.com/women/a33564557/alysia-montano-is-the-hero-of-this-story/" target="_blank" ><u>Pregnancy is not an illness</u></a>," says Alysia Montaño and at these last games (and the past games), mom athletes came out and proved it. In fact, <a href="https://www.olympedia.org/lists/77/manual" target="_blank" ><u>22 Olympians have competed with a baby bump</u></a>. </p><ul>
  <li><a href="https://www.insider.com/pregnant-heptathlete-lindsay-flach-competed-in-olympic-trials-2021-7" target="_blank" ><u>Lindsay Flach</u></a> competed in the 2020 Olympic trials with an 18-week baby bump</li>
  <li>Martina Valcepina won bronze at the 2014 Sochi games while pregnant with twins</li>
  <li>Nur Suryani Binti Mohamed Taibi competed in the 2012 games while 34-weeks pregnant </li>
  <li>Cornelia Pfohl competed twice while pregnant! Once in 2000 (winning bronze) and again in the 2004 Olympics while 30 weeks pregnant</li>
</ul><p>You probably saw a picture of runner, Alysia Montaño. She’s been dubbed the “pregnant runner”. Her photo recently resurfaced from the 2014 USATF Outdoor Championships of Montaño running the 800m while eight months pregnant. Not only is she an incredible athlete, but she launched the nonprofit, <a href="https://andmother.org/" target="_blank" ><u>&Mother</u></a>, an organization aimed to support a woman’s choice to pursue a career and motherhood. </p>

<p>These all-star women are showing the world that life (and fitness) doesn't stop when you have a pregnant belly. You can grow a new life and still compete in the highest arenas. <strong>And that is incredible!</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_b1348d2fa6724781ae187fc1cdc55a21~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_980,h_676,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Montaño running the 800m at the 2014 USATF Outdoor Championships. EZRA SHAW/GETTY IMAGES" alt="Pregnant woman running at competition event"></figure><p>Catching up with our own athlete, Stax instructor Alex, we talked about how her fitness changed during and after pregnancy.</p>

<p>In 2020, Alex was just one of the over <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/443051/number-of-births-in-canada/" target="_blank" ><u>370,000 Canadian women</u></a> and over <a href="https://www.cdc.gov/nchs/fastats/births.htm" target="_blank" ><u>3,747,000 women in the US</u></a> to give birth. And like so many other women, Alex underwent a massive adjustment in how she practiced and viewed fitness during pregnancy.  </p>
<h2>Staying active during pregnancy</h2>
<p>Sharing the same sentiments as Montaño, Alex said "being pregnant isn’t a handicap but it’s an experience." </p>

<p>There’s a common misconception when it comes to being motherhood that you shouldn’t be exercising while pregnant. But she knew that staying fit and staying healthy while pregnant was the best thing for her baby. </p>

<p>In fact, the <a href="https://www.acog.org/womens-health/faqs/exercise-during-pregnancy" target="_blank" >American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists recommends</a> pregnant women get at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity exercise every week - like <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/virtual-studio" target="_blank" ><u>stationary biking</u></a>.</p>

<p>But being active didn't mean pushing herself to the same limits as pre-pregnancy.</p>
<h3>Alex's 4 tips on how to stay healthy during pregnancy</h3>
<p>Alex shares her 4 tips for staying fit during pregnancy:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Listen to your body</strong>. Things start to hurt but acknowledge and respect that discomfort. On days when she felt nauseated, she rested.</li>
  <li><strong>Adapt exercise to how your body hurts</strong>. When she experienced back pain during pregnancy, she stopped doing standing sprints on the <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/5-best-spin-bikes-for-home" target="_blank" ><u>spin bike</u></a>. </li>
  <li><strong>Check-in with yourself mentally</strong>. Learn which days to take a break and give your body the rest that it needs, vs. the days where you may just be feeling lazy or not motivated. Any movement is good movement!</li>
  <li><strong>Check-in with yourself physically</strong>. If something feels wrong, don’t push through physical pains or injuries. </li>
</ul> <h2>Getting back into fitness after pregnancy</h2>
<p>After the miracle of growing a new life and then giving birth, Alex admitted that she fell back onto old thought patterns and wanted to push herself and go, go, go! But quickly she realized that she was going to make some adjustments. </p><blockquote>Have patience with yourself. Have patience with your body. </blockquote><p> Being a mom makes you a warrior, and giving yourself that grace to accept your new body (and your new life) is important. </p>
<h3>Alex's 4 tips for Fitness after pregnancy</h3><ul>
  <li><strong>Do core exercises for engagement and activation.</strong> Keep your core muscles engaged during all exercise</li>
  <li><strong>Go to pelvic floor physical therapy</strong> - the greatest thing you could ever do is discover your pelvic floor. Go as soon as you get pregnant and throughout your pregnancy (hello kegel exercises!)</li>
  <li><strong>Take what you can get.</strong> It’s okay if you don’t get the workout in because the time will come. There are going to be weeks at a time that you can’t exercise. Make your mental health a priority. Walking is a great way to get out of the house and is amazing cardio for your mental wellness</li>
  <li><strong>Celebrate the changes.</strong> We celebrate the fact that you lost 20 lbs after a baby way more than we celebrate the fact that your body created life. There’s so much power in being a woman and owning that.</li>
</ul> <p>Not everyone has to compete on the world stage. Staying fit and healthy before, during, and after your pregnancy should be a priority. But in this day of toxic social media remember: fitness will come, weight loss will come, strength will come, whatever it is you need, it will come. </p>

<p>Being fit and healthy means everything to Alex. It means longevity, mental wellbeing, being a better wife, a better mother, and a better friend. </p>

<p>When Alex needs to take the time and be reminded that she is so much more than "just a mom", coming to the Stax studio helps her feel that and makes her feel amazing. </p>
 
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Best Spin Bikes for Home]]></title><description><![CDATA[You've probably been told about the amazing indoor cycle classes your friends have been raving about - those Stax Cycle classes that is!...]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/5-best-spin-bikes-for-home</link><guid isPermaLink="false">610997e0ea3bce0015d52d1a</guid><category><![CDATA[fitness equipment]]></category><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 14:09:09 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_1be4fddf969c47d0a040517e4db6b826~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You've probably been told about the amazing indoor cycle classes your friends have been raving about - those Stax Cycle classes that is! We're here to share the love of indoor spin with the world! It all starts with the spin bike. Here are the 5 best spin bikes for at home! </p>

<p>Whether you have tried us out in the studio, heard raving reviews from a friend, or just want to try a fun indoor cycling class, Stax spin classes are a great way to get your heart pumpin'.</p>

<p>Over the last year, we've seen that having your own at home spin bike can help keep you on top of your <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/5-ways-to-keep-your-summer-fitness-goals-on-track" target="_blank" >,<u>fitness goals</u></a>. Dialing in to your favorite <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/on-demand" target="_blank" >,<u>on-demand class</u></a> can make you feel like you're crushing it with your friends. Regardless of your motivations, we're happy to be sharing our love of spinning workouts.</p>
<h2>5 Best Indoor Spin Bikes</h2>
<p>We've compiled a list of the 5 best indoor spin bikes.</p>

<p>This list ranges from the splurge-worthy bikes you see on your Stax screen to budget friendly choices. We also share the pros and cons of each bike so you can make the best selection for you. </p>
<h3>1. Stages SC3 and SC1 - Worth the Splurge</h3>
<p>First up is our favorite - the <a href="https://dotmarfitness.com/collections/indoor-cycle/products/stages-sc3-cycle-bike" target="_blank" ><u>Stages SC3 </u></a>and <a href="https://dotmarfitness.com/collections/indoor-cycle/products/stages-sc1-cycle-bike" target="_blank" ><u>SC1</u></a>. Here at Stax, we ride the Stages SC3 indoor bike with the <a href="https://dotmarfitness.com/products/stages-sp2-pedals?_pos=4&#38;_sid=53d7523b5&#38;_ss=r" target="_blank" ><u>Stages SP2 Pedal</u></a> . This is the ultimate indoor studio bike but is definitely a splurge. </p>

<p>This bike is ideal for the serious rider who is truly committed to the spin lifestyle and wants the ultimate studio experience. The SC1 is a similar model with a slightly lower price point a few less features. </p>

<p>The best part? Our friends at <a href="https://dotmarfitness.com/" target="_blank" ><u>Dotmar Fitness</u></a> are offering Stax members free shipping for all Stages bikes & accessories (promo code "Staxcycle").</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_26415f24207d440e9684bce23bffeb67~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_561,h_482,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Stages SC3 indoor cycling bike. Photo from Stages" alt="Stages SC3 indoor cycling bike"></figure><p><strong>Pros:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>No choreo modifications required with this bike - follow along with your favorite instructor with ease</li>
  <li>SprintShift (macro-level resistance changer)<strong> </strong>to dial up the intensity</li>
  <li>Easily adjust the set-up to customize the bike's settings</li>
  <li>EcoSCRN display so you can track your stats</li>
  <li>10-year warranty</li>
</ul><p><strong>Cons:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>Pricey</li>
</ul><h3>Schwinn IC4 Indoor Cycling Bike - Best for any rider</h3>
<p>Next up is the <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/dp/B07WZXSDKW/ref=as_sl_pc_qf_sp_asin_til?tag=staxcycleclub-20&#38;linkCode=w00&#38;linkId=26fbc8f3355774b125e68da4a5a7b3c2&#38;creativeASIN=B07WZXSDKW" target="_blank" ><u>Schwinn IC4 indoor cycling bike</u></a>. But really, any of the Schwinn indoor bike series are a great option for beginners and spinning pros. </p>

<p>We love the Schwinn IC4 because it has some great features that make it perfectly suited for all spin classes. Plus, Schwinn bikes are affordable and readily available at local retailers without waiting for delivery. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_42f28026058a46d2b1bd625c069e1fa5~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_735,h_793,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Schwinn IC4 indoor cycle bike. Photo from Amazon." alt="Schwinn IC4 indoor cycle bike"></figure><p><strong>Pros:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>100 levels of magnetic resistance allows you to tailor your workout's intensity</li>
  <li>Foot pedals come standard with toe cages or clips</li>
  <li>Bluetooth connectivity + tablet holder makes it easy to connect to your Stax virtual class</li>
  <li>Easy access dumbbell cradles (perfect for the weight track)</li>
  <li>Full color and backlit LCD console monitor</li>
</ul><p><strong>Cons:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>No macro-level resistance changer</li>
  <li>No low bar handles </li>
</ul><h3>Echelon Connect Indoor Spin Bike <strong>- Under $1000</strong></h3>
<p>The Echelon Connect indoor spin bike is an affordable option that is available online or through <a href="https://www.walmart.ca/en/ip/echelon-connect-sport-indoor-spin-bike-with-30-day-free-echelon-united-membership/6000201499355" target="_blank" ><u>Walmart</u></a> or <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/dp/B08MY4QLMC/ref=as_sl_pc_qf_sp_asin_til?tag=staxcycleclub-20&#38;linkCode=w00&#38;linkId=9cca5b29e44c30d4c5588a1c91b414f5&#38;creativeASIN=B08MY4QLMC" target="_blank" ><u>Amazon</u></a>! This bike is priced right at under $1,000. </p>

<p>The Echelon spin bike has everything you need for the ultimate spin class plus it has a small footprint (great for smaller spaces). Easy adjustable features let you customize your ride set-up. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_3c6ba2b79f9442408d54a75cd08a1cc2~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="Echelon Connect Sport Indoor Spin Bike. Photo from Amazon" alt="Echelon Connect Sport Indoor Spin Bike"></figure><p><strong>Pros:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>32 levels of resistance</li>
  <li>Sleek, modern design</li>
  <li>Fully adjustable toe cages on the pedals for a secure fit</li>
  <li>Anti-slip handlebars with a tablet holder</li>
</ul><p><strong>Cons:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>No macro-level resistance changer</li>
  <li>No low bar handles </li>
  <li>No dumbbell cradle</li>
  <li>Pedals are not compatible with clip-in shoes</li>
</ul><h3>YONKFUL Indoor Cycling Bike - Under $500</h3>
<p>This adjustable indoor exercise bike is a great starter bike and is priced under $500. </p>

<p>The <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/dp/B08CVS1Y6D/ref=as_sl_pc_qf_sp_asin_til?tag=staxcycleclub-20&#38;linkCode=w00&#38;linkId=c555c233dc92d057d9adeaf7f154a0ac&#38;creativeASIN=B08CVS1Y6D" target="_blank" ><u>YONKFUL indoor cycling bike</u></a> is a perfect bike for newbies or those who are testing the waters of indoor cycling and don't want to invest a whole lot into their first bike. This spin bike has everything you need to misbehave in one of Stax's on-demand classes. </p><figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_d9e5f9747ac74ef39c660a6f27c6673d~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" title="YONKFUL Exercises Bike. Photo from Amazon." alt="YONKFUL Exercises Bike. "></figure><p><strong>Pros:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>LCD monitor to track your stats + a handy tablet holder</li>
  <li>Adjustable resistance to turn up the intensity</li>
  <li>Transportation wheels</li>
  <li>Fully adjustable to customize your ride set-up</li>
</ul><p><strong>Cons:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>No macro-level resistance changer</li>
  <li>No low bar handles </li>
  <li>No dumbbell cradle</li>
  <li>Pedals are not compatible with clip-in shoes</li>
</ul><h3>Soozier Stationary Exercise Bike - Budget Friendly</h3>
<p>Last up on our list of the best spin bikes for at home is the <a href="https://www.amazon.ca/dp/B08YS92VSZ/ref=as_sl_pc_qf_sp_asin_til?tag=staxcycleclub-20&#38;linkCode=w00&#38;linkId=2512bfcadaa08470246a141d7d0ba8dc&#38;creativeASIN=B08YS92VSZ" target="_blank" ><u>Soozier stationary exercise bike</u></a>. This is the most budget friendly option and the best spin bike under $200. The Soozier is a great bike to get anyone started on the thrill of indoor spin cycle. </p>

<p>This exercise bike has an 18 pound flywheel which is about half of the other spin bike options. The <a href="https://cyclefromhome.com/choosing-the-right-flywheel-weight-for-your-spin-bike/" target="_blank" ><u>flywheel</u></a> is what maintains a smooth and safe operation during your spin bike workout. So, the heavier the flywheel, the smoother the ride. For newbies, this lighter weight flywheel will be sufficient. </p>

<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/85bcec_77e1a63522ee486c81d4847a1e846b6f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_480,h_480,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p><strong>Pros:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>LCD monitor to track your stats + a handy tablet holder</li>
  <li>Adjustable resistance to turn up the intensity</li>
  <li>Fully adjustable to customize your ride</li>
  <li>Transportation wheels</li>
</ul><p><strong>Cons:</strong></p><ul>
  <li>No macro-level resistance changer</li>
  <li>No low bar handles or dumbbell cradle</li>
  <li>Pedals are not compatible with clip-in shoes</li>
  <li>Lighter flywheel may result in a less-smooth ride</li>
</ul><hr><p>Do you own an outdoor bike and want to use it instead of investing in an indoor cycle bike? Convert your pedal bike with a <a href="https://www.amazon.com/BalanceFrom-Trainer-Bicycle-Exercise-Magnetic/dp/B0872255PS/ref=sr_1_5?dchild=1&#38;keywords=bike+trainer+stand&#38;qid=1628030620&#38;sr=8-5" target="_blank" ><u>bike trainer stand</u></a>. </p>

<p>With these great options, spin cycle exercise is more accessible than ever before. Regardless of the bike you choose, we are excited to have you join the Stax family.</p>

<p>Now, it's time to clip in for your badass spin class! #LETSMISBEHAVE</p>
 ]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Ways to Keep Your Summer Fitness Goals on Track]]></title><description><![CDATA[Are you starting to feel the summer temptation? The itch to leave workouts behind and give in to the beverages by the pool and late-night...]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/5-ways-to-keep-your-summer-fitness-goals-on-track</link><guid isPermaLink="false">60f24c67aca979001508123f</guid><category><![CDATA[fitness + wellness]]></category><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 15:57:18 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_1bfaa5f3456a42a4a52f7ad4b13523b7~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you starting to feel the summer temptation? The itch to leave workouts behind and give in to the beverages by the pool and late-night social snacks. US TOO!</p>
<p> </p>
<p>All those sweaty, hardcore workouts can’t be for nothing. Even with the hot sun beaming down on you, don’t let yourself fall behind and slowly lose sight of what it is you’ve been working towards: your sexy wellness goals.</p>

<p>Since balance is key, here's 5 easy ways you can stick to your fitness goals and maintain your incredible strength, mental stamina, and feeling unstoppable as you hit up those summer activities...hike or SUP anyone?!</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/f38575_1bfaa5f3456a42a4a52f7ad4b13523b7~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><h2>5 Ways to Stay on Track With Your Fitness Goals</h2>
<p>We are all for misbehaving... but sometimes you have to behave. Here are 5 badass ways to stay on track with your fitness goals this summer. </p>

<h3>1.  Pre-Schedule Your Workouts</h3><p> </p>
<p>If you’re finding it hard to stick to your fitness goals during the nice weather, try planning your workouts just as you do the rest of your day. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>Planning gives your brain the idea that you are obligated to do something. Whether you write it on your calendar or just make a mental note that today, at 4 pm, you are joining the workout class, it will help you. Your brain wants to execute plans, and if you tell it to, it will.</p>

<p>Stax is here to support your fitness goals. We offer your favorite spin classes and heart pumping workouts in <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/virtual-studio" target="_blank" ><u>our virtual studio</u></a> so you can schedule in a little me time. Enjoy your fitness anytime, anywhere.</p>

<p>This type of commitment is the best way to follow through with your summer fitness goals and makes it easier for you to get in the zone.</p>
<h3>2.  Consume Healthy Super Foods</h3><p> </p>
<p>Healthy bodies are made in the kitchen. Even if you can stick to a workout plan and stay on track inside the studio, an even more crucial part of attaining your fitness goals is to eat healthy and well.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Superfoods are the best way to get your body the nutrients it needs while still giving you the right amount of carbs, protein, and vitamins alike. The benefits of great foods go above and beyond what any workout routine can offer.</p>

<p>Being healthy outside of the gym is where you’ll really see your body and fitness levels prosper. Maintaining a fitness schedule but eating unhealthy foods will give you a "two steps forward, one step back" type of routine. If you want your time working out to pay off, the rest of your lifestyle should follow.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Eating well and training hard go hand in hand to help you reach your summer fitness goals.</p>

<p>If you're wanting to learn more about Superfoods, keep your eyes peeled for our next blog post where we'll dive into the top 100!</p>
<h3>3.  HOLLA AT an Accountability Partner</h3><p> </p>
<p>A workout buddy, a gym pal, whatever you may call this person... every gym-goer needs someone who holds them accountable for their actions. If you skip a session, you’d better believe they’ll be all over you about it.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Accountability partners or gym buddies, push you to follow through with your word and attend the sessions you sign up for. Not only are you letting yourself down if you decide to stay home, but now someone else is waiting for you to show up.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Your accountability partner could be a friend you see at the gym most days or even your favorite Stax instructor! Help your friends meet their fitness goals and they’ll likely do the same for you. Accountability is a big responsibility, and no one wants to stand up their workout partner!</p>
<p> </p><h3>4.  Choose Motivating Exercise</h3><p> </p>
<p>Exercise is not the same on everyone’s body, and we all have a favorite spin class, stackable workout, or exercise activity that really gets our blood pumping.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>If an outdoor run or weight lifting session doesn't fire you up today, try out gyms and workout classes that excite you! There are so many options! You can be as picky as you want until you find a style that gets you out of bed in the morning.</p>

<p>Stax Cycle offers incredible beat infused, <a href="https://www.staxcycleclub.com/stackables" target="_blank" ><u>high intensity workouts</u></a> that are designed to define and tone your entire body with minimal equipment. Our express workouts are built to be stacked, so you can dig deep and give your body exactly what it needs. Some days it might be 1 quick workout or some days you might stack 2 or 3!</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Dreading a workout is no way to maintain a schedule and keep up your summer fitness. Stay on track and be happy to do it!</p>
<p> </p><h3>5.  Set Goals – And Never Give Up on Yourself</h3><p> </p>
<p>Finally, don’t be so hard on yourself. This past year has been a roller coaster for everyone and may not be where you thought you would.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Instead of feeling down about this, get back up and try again. Whichever fitness level you find yourself at, set reachable goals for the short and long term, and find a way to reach them. After each plan you surpass, you’ll be left feeling badass and fitter than ever.</p>
 
<p>Upholding fitness goals in the hot summers is not easy, but you weren’t made for easy. You were made to slay your summer goals! #LETSMISBEHAVE</p>

<p>Stax's on-demand platform hosts our real, raw + unrehearsed collection of our spin + sculpt library, along with other bonus content to keep the fire burning, whenever and wherever it works for you!</p> 
]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Wellness Challenge Feature #3: "The Real Life Approach to Performance Nutrition" with Jana]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hi Stax! I'm Jana, a fitness enthusiast and lover of all things food, I support my clients to improve their relationship with food, their...]]></description><link>https://www.staxcycleclub.com/post/wellness-challenge-feature-3-the-real-life-approach-to-performance-nutrition-with-jana</link><guid isPermaLink="false">603c42c85cecda001792ed14</guid><category><![CDATA[healthy lifestyle]]></category><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 13:30:43 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_8d8c958f005844dcb3c3c61a99b323a8~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_518,h_388,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>Stax Fam</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hi Stax!</p>

<p>I'm Jana, a fitness enthusiast and lover of all things food, I support my clients to improve their relationship with food, their body, and movement. I am lucky enough to work with an incredibly talented team of registered dietitians who each have specialized areas of practice at <a href="www.HealthStandNutrition.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>Health Stand Nutrition Consulting Inc.</u></a> </p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_8d8c958f005844dcb3c3c61a99b323a8~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_518,h_388,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>As a retired high-level athlete, I had the chance to experience the impact that nutrition can have on sport performance, body composition, and recovery. I have since completed the Advanced Sport Nutrition Certification through the Dietitians of Canada and the Canadian Sports Institute. As my career progressed, I further specialized to bring a fun and balanced approach to nutrition. I work mainly with athletes, recovering dieters, mental health clients and individuals struggling with eating disorders. </p>

<p>I am currently working towards my Master of Arts in Counselling Psychology to further my abilities to support my clients using a whole person approach.</p>

<p><strong>My philosophy:</strong> Supporting athletes and exercise enthusiasts to use nutrition as their competitive edge while maintaining a healthy relationship with food, exercise, and the body.</p>
<p>I believe that the healthiest life is one that can honestly enjoy!</p>

<p><strong>So let's dive into performance nutrition!</strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/a27d70_2077dc8bcc7247fe99b5a05145b22590~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_359,h_542,al_c,q_80/file.png"  ></figure><p>Performance nutrition, or sports nutrition, refers to how we use food to fuel ourselves towards our fitness related goals. </p>

<p>However, contrary to popular belief, it really does'nt have to be that hard and</p>
<p>there is no "perfect" way to do it! </p>

<p>The real life approach to performance nutrition means finding what makes you feel your best and works for you.</p>




<p>Here are the key elements that are essential for peak performance:</p>

<p><strong>1. Your Everyday Fuelling</strong></p>
<p>Before changing nutrition patterns around your workouts, make sure you are eat a balanced diet (including protein, carbohydrates, fats, and lots of colourful foods) throughout the day ensuring you eat enough to keep your energy up. Also, please remember to eat foods you enjoy. There is so much more to food than simply fuelling. All foods have a place in your life and should be something we enjoy, not dread!</p>

<p><strong>2. Hydration</strong></p>
<p>Carry a water bottle with you wherever you go (in your car, on your desk, in your workout bag, etc) to ensure you get enough water throughout your day.</p>
<p>Don't get me wrong, I encourage enjoying your coffee, tea, wine, or cocktail of choice moderately, but let's ensure the water is happening too! If you are dehydrated before you even start your workout, you will not perform your best or get the same benefits from all that hard work.</p>

<p><strong>3. Pre-Workout Nutrition</strong></p>
<p>Everyone is totally different with this one, so by all means, if what you are doing already feels like it is working, then keep doing it!</p>

<p>If you are struggling with energy during your workouts then let's talk.</p>

<p>Depending on the timing of your exercise, you may be having a full meal or an intentional snack to support your energy needs. If you are having a full meal before your exercise, you will want to eat about 2-4 hours beforehand to allow enough time for digestion and energy production. This meal should include an easily digestible protein, a substantial source of carbohydrate, lower fats, and lower fibre. This helps support faster digestion as fibre and fats are slower to digest. Fat and fibre are essential to an overall healthy diet so they should not be limited outside of your pre and post workout fuelling.</p>

<p>Here are some meal ideas that I find work great before (2-4 hours) workouts:</p>

<p>- Cooked rice, soya sauce, miso-glazed cod, and green peas</p>
<p>- Bagel with 2 scrambled eggs, a little shredded cheese, and an orange</p>
<p>- Tuna melt with roasted veggies</p>
<p>- Quinoa bowl with sweet potatoes, hummus, beets, guacamole, shredded carrots & chicken</p>

<p>If you are exercising after work or more than 4 hours after your last meal, you may need a substantial snack including carbohydrates for energy. Here are some of my faves:</p>

<p>- Crackers and hummus</p>
<p>- Apple and nut butter</p>
<p>- Homemade granola bar or energy balls</p>
<p>- Half a sandwich</p>

<p>If you are a hungry all the time person like me, you might want a little top up of energy right before your movement of choice! Make sure to choose a simple energy snack you actually like! Here are some of my faves:</p>

<p>- Fruit or dried fruit</p>
<p>- Crackers such as graham crackers or arrowroot crackers</p>
<p>- Fruit snacks or jujubes (my personal favs)</p>

<p><strong>4. Post-Workout Recovery</strong></p>
<p>Intentional recovery is essential to performance improvements and ensuring adequate energy for movement next time! </p>

<p>The keys to good recovery after a high intensity workout include: </p>

<p><strong>- Timing  - </strong>Ideally, you do want to consume your post workout refuel as soon as possible after the workout. Especially if your goal is strength increase or muscle gain, shoot for within 30 minutes after your workout.  </p>

<p><strong>- Include a protein source - </strong>Greek yogurt, cottage cheese, protein powder, meat, fish, eggs, beans, legumes... whatever works for you! </p>

<p><strong>- Don't be scared of Carbs - </strong>Replenishing your muscles with carbohydrates supports better energy, less muscle fatigue, and you will head into your next activity feeling more recovered and ready to go. </p>

<p><strong>- Hydration - </strong>It's back again! Re-hydrate with water after your workout, even if you drank water during your workout. </p>


<p>If you want to know more specifics about your ideal recovery meal or snack, check out : <a href="https://www.healthstandnutrition.com/sports-nutrition-recovery-what-to-eat-after-a-workout/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.healthstandnutrition.com/sports-nutrition-recovery-what-to-eat-after-a-workout/</u></a></p>

<p>And remember...even if you are working towards changes in your body composition, you do not want to skimp on the recovery meal!</p>

<p>If you are looking for more nutrion information, check out these links from the blog posts on the Health Stand Nutrition website. </p>

<p>Back to the Basics of Sport Nutrition :</p>
<p><a href="https://www.healthstandnutrition.com/sports-dietitian-tips-sports-nutrition/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.healthstandnutrition.com/sports-dietitian-tips-sports-nutrition/</u></a></p>

<p>Three tips for Improving Your Body Confidence </p>
<p><a href="https://www.healthstandnutrition.com/body-confidence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.healthstandnutrition.com/body-confidence/</u></a></p>

<p>Fuelling Ideas for Outdoor Activities </p>
<p><a href="https://www.healthstandnutrition.com/foods-for-hiking/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>https://www.healthstandnutrition.com/foods-for-hiking/</u></a></p>

<p>Thanks so much for following along, if you're interested in connecting further, my contact info is below!</p>

<p>Jana</p>

<p><strong>Jana Spindler, BSc RD </strong></p>
<p>Registered Dietitian & Nutrition Counsellor </p>
<p>@janaspindler_rd</p>

<p>Health Stand Nutrition Consulting Inc.</p>
<p>Phone: <u>(403) 262-3466</u></p>
<p><a href="https://www.healthstandnutrition.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><u>www.HealthStandNutrition.com</u></a></p>


]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>